#I see trees of green #
#我看见树的翠绿 #
#Red roses too #
#和玫瑰的红艳 #
#I see them bloom #
#她们为你和我 #
#For me and you #
#而绽放#
#And I think to myself #
片名：《寻堡奇遇２》 #我心中想着 #
#What a wonderful world #
#多么美好的世界啊 #
#I see skies of blue #
#我看到了蓝天 #
#And clouds of white #
#与白云 #
#The bright blessed day #
#明亮、幸福的一天 #
#The dark sacred night #
#夜晚向人们道晚安 #
#And I think to myself #
#我心中想着 #
#What a wonderful world #
#多么美好的世界啊 #
#Yes #
#是的#
#I think to myself #
#我心中想着 #
#What a wonderful #
#多么美好的 #
Yes, dude!
好爽！
What the fuck? What the fuck? What are you doing?
搞什么？搞什么？你干嘛啊？
I'm taking the most incredible dump of all time, man.
我这回可是史无前例的大清仓了，伙计
You couldn't wait till I got out of the shower?
你就不能等我洗完了再说？
May I remind you that we both just ate 30 burgers...
难道你忘了咱俩刚刚吃了30个汉堡包
and four large orders of fries?
外加四分大号薯条了么？
Don't worry, in a little bit, I'm sure it'll hit you too.
别担心，再过一小会儿就轮到你了
It may be. But I'm gonna wait till you get out of the shower.
就算是，我也会等你洗完再解决
Well, don't wait too long. We've got to leave for the airport in an hour.
那可别等太久，咱们一个小时内就得去机场了
Ooh, that burns.
哦，好刺激
- An hour? - Hey, and, Roldy?
- 一小时？ - 嘿，对了，罗迪？
Yeah?
怎么了？
Nice pubes.
毛毛蛮可爱
Asshole, get out of here right now.
衰人，赶紧出去
- Wipe and leave. Wipe and leave now! - Dude, this thing is huge!
- 擦屁股走人，动作快点！ - 哥们儿，这条有够大啊！
I think it still has cheese on it.
我估计上面还粘着奶酪呢！
dude. Oh, my Go... I just realized something.
兄弟，天，我想起一件事
What?
什么？
Maria's gonna think I'm a stalker, man. I'm following her to Amsterdam.
玛丽亚会把我当变态看的 我跟她跟到阿姆斯特丹
Dude, relax. I have a med school interview in ten minutes.
老兄，放松点儿 十分钟内我就去参加医学院的面试了
You don't see me freaking out.
我都没慌
Don't worry, man, she'll be psyched to see you.
别瞎操心了，她等你的心澎湃着呢
Oh, psyched? You think she's gonna be psyched?
噢，澎湃？你认为她会很激动？
Totes, dude. Why wouldn't she be?
废话，不激动行么？
So how does this work?
这次如何行动？
We just... we show up in Amsterdam and we start calling hotels...
咱们到了阿姆斯特丹，然后打酒店电话
and ask if they have a Maria staying there?
询问是否有位玛丽亚入住？
- I don't even know her last name. - Dude, it's totally cool.
- 我连她的姓都不知道 - 这才有意思
We're definitely gonna find her.
咱们肯定能找着她
Amsterdam is a very small place. It's not gonna be...
阿姆斯特丹是个小地方，不会…
Sir, I need you to step aside, please. Let me search you.
先生，请您后退一下，我要对您进行搜查
- Did I beep? - No, you didn't beep.
- 报警器响了？ - 不，没有响
Just a random security check.
只是随机安全抽查
If you could just step aside, please? Just over here.
您能否站到这边来？
- Random, huh? - Yeah.
- 随机，哈？ - 是的
So this has nothing to do with my ethnicity?
这么说和我的种族无关了？
Kumar, just do what the guy says.
库马，听他的就是了
Sir, it's our job as airport security...
先生，我们机场安检人员的工作职责
to search for all possible weapons or illegal drugs.
便是搜查一切可能的武器或非法药品
So just because of the color of my skin, you assume that I have drugs on me?
你就因为我的肤色而推测我携带毒品？
- No, he's... - What are you, a racist?
- 不，他只是… - 你是什么人，种族主义者？
Racist? Dude, I'm black.
种族主义？兄弟，我是黑人
He's black. He's not a racist.
他是黑人，不是种族主义者
Please, dude, you're barely even brown.
别搞笑了，兄弟，你几乎算棕色的了
No, he didn't mean that.
不，他不是这个意思
Compared to me, you look like Matthew Perry.
跟我比，他长得就像马修・派瑞
Hey, who you calling Matthew Perry, bitch?
嘿，你管谁叫马修・派瑞呢，贱人？
I'm calling you Matthew Perry, you Matthew Perry-looking bitch!
说你呢，马修・派瑞 你个马修・派瑞样的贱货！
No, there's nobody here who is Matthew Perry. No one!
没有，没人是马修・派瑞，都不是！
What is going on here?
怎么了？
Sir, Matthew Perry over here thinks that I have illegal narcotics on me...
先生，这位马修・派瑞认为我携带违禁药品
because I'm a minority.
就因为我的种族
This is textbook racial profiling...
这是典型的种族脸谱化
and I'd be more than happy to call the ACLU or the government...
我很乐意给美国公民自由协会或政府打个电话…
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Sorry for the inconvenience, sir.
不不不不不，抱歉给您添麻烦了，先生
- You can move along. - I appreciate it. Thanks, Matt Perry.
- 您可以通过了 - 非常感谢，多谢了，马修・派瑞
Hey, what are you doing?
你怎么回事？
What do you mean, what am I doing? He called me Matthew Perry.
你什么意思，我怎么回事？ 他管我叫马修・派瑞
Well, you look like Matthew Perry.
对啊，你就是很像马修・派瑞
- He's white! - So what?
- 他是白人啊！ - 那又怎么样？
Why does everything have to become a huge argument with you, man?
你干嘛跟别人过不去啊？
'Cause this is America, dude...
因为这是美国，伙计…
and as long as I have my freedom of speech, no one's gonna shut me up.
只要我有说话的自由，就没人敢让我闭嘴
Kumar?
库马？
Roldy?
罗迪？
- Vanessa. - Oh, my God!
- 瓦内萨 - 真是巧啊！
- Good to see you. - So good to see you. L...
- 见到你太好了 - 见到你真好
- Hi. Hey. - Hey.
- 嗨，嘿 - 嘿
Hey.
嗨
God, it's been forever. What are you guys doing?
天啊，都几百年没见了，你们这是去哪儿？
We're actually on our way to Amsterdam.
我们要去阿姆斯特丹
- Amsterdam? - Yeah.
- 阿姆斯特丹？ - 是啊
Well, you guys haven't changed.
你们俩还是老样子
You have. You look amazing. Your hair is diff...
你变了，你真抢眼，你的头发…
- doesn't she look amazing? - Yeah.
- 她是不是很抢眼？ - 对啊
Yeah, you look great. You look awesome. Sorry.
是啊，你样子好极了，相当有魅力，抱歉
What am I even saying? You look different and...
我在说些什么啊，你看起来与众不同…
- Kumar Patel, you're flustered. - Little bit.
- 库玛・巴特尔，你语无伦次了 - 有点儿
So, what's up with you? You still dating the Abercrombie-wearing douchebag?
你怎么样？还在跟那个臭显摆的贱男谈着么？
Actually, it's Brooks Brothers.
其实，是和布鲁克斯兄弟
Colton! How are you, buddy?
克尔顿！你还好吗，哥们儿？
- Good to see ya. - Good to see you.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
And we're not dating anymore.
我们没在谈了
No. We... are getting married.
不，我们要…结婚了
Congratulations, you guys.
恭喜啊，二位
- You're fucking getting married? - Yeah.
- 你们他妈要结婚了 - 没错
- When? - Next week.
- 什么时候？ - 下周
It's going to be a perfect day.
将会是绝美的一天
I mean, that's assuming we get those Stargazer lilies for the bouquets.
我看，用占星百合做花束太夸张了吧
This florist has been a complete nightmare.
这个花商真是够阴险
Fucking assholes.
够缺德
Colton's practically planning the whole wedding all by himself.
婚礼算是克尔顿一个人在亲手操办
So, Rold, Brewster Keegan letting you off the leash for a little vay-cay?
罗德，这么说布鲁斯特解开链子放你出来撒欢了？
I own that place now, Colton.
现在我自己当老板了，克尔顿
Thank you so much for the hook-up.
多谢关注
Hey, I ran into Todd, at Whitaker's, of course.
对了，我在惠特克那儿碰见陶德
He told me you got a job working for the government.
他说你在政府工作
Yeah! Yeah, President Bush and my dad were in the same fraternity.
对啊！没错，布什总统我爸曾是联谊会同学
- Oh, that's right. - Oh, Jesus.
- 真够厉害 - 天啊
Yeah, yeah, when he gave my dad that appointment at the defense department...
是啊是啊，他跟我爸在国防部会面之后
- I became his right-hand man. - Douche.
- 我就成了他的得力助手 - 扯
The President's supposed to be at our wedding...
总统可能会出席我们的婚礼
- but you know how busy he is. - Yeah.
- 不过你们知道他日理万机 - 是啊
Sounds like an incredible job, man.
你这工作真牛啊，兄弟
Hey, you really got some major connections to the top.
你真是混到最上头了
If you ever need anything, I'm your man.
你们有什么事要帮忙，一定开口
- Thank you so much, buddy. - Anytime.
- 谢谢了，哥们儿 - 一定
This guy's the best.
还是这哥们儿厉害
- So, sweetheart, we should get going. - Yes.
- 那，甜心，咱们该走了 - 是呀
- Good to see you guys again. - Congratulations again.
- 很开心在这能碰见你们 - 再次恭喜
- Thank you. Take care, thank you. - It's so nice.
- 多谢，保重，谢谢 - 真不错
- Bye.
- 再会
Dude, I can't believe they're getting married.
老兄，真不敢相信他们竟然要结婚了
We've only been broken up two years.
我们才分手两年
Plus that dude has date-rape face.
再说那家伙还长了一张淫荡的脸
I don't even know what that is.
没听说过什么是淫荡的脸
One who possesses the face of a date rapist.
就是长了一幅强奸犯的脸孔
Right. Listen...
好吧，行了…
I'm sorry, bro.
我也替你难过，兄弟
But we are going to Amsterdam. Come on.
但咱们要去阿姆斯特丹了，来吧
This is true. This is true, Roldy.
确实，确实，罗迪.
- Man, this is so not like me. - Yeah.
- 这不是我的风格 - 没错
It's like I'm a whole new Harold. Better, faster, stronger.
我好像换了个人，更优，更快，更强
Nice.
不错
Man, I've never used a sick day before.
我从来没请过病假
I'm taking a whole week off from work here, man.
一下子请了整整一周的假，哥们
And in less than eight hours, we're gonna be in Amsterdam.
而且，用不了八小时，咱们就在阿姆斯特丹了
- This is nuts. This is nuts. - I know, dude.
- 真疯狂，真疯狂 - 了解，兄弟
It's gonna be exactly like Euro Tr/p, only it's not gonna suck.
简直就是《欧洲性旅行》，不过咱们不会倒霉
- It's gonna be awesome. - It's not not gonna be awesome.
- 我们会过瘾 - 不过瘾都不行
Dude. Dude, this chick's giving me such a boner, it's awesome.
哥们哥们，这妞很带劲儿，相当正点
Thank you. You ruined the moment.
多谢，破坏我的思绪
She's all yours, buddy.
她属于你，老兄
- You wanna pause it? - I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
- 要暂停么？ - 我去洗手间
No, that's...
不，这个…
Enjoy.
你看吧
Just a minute.
等等
Fuc...
靠…
Hey, hey.
嘿，嘿
Let me in.
让我进来
What are you doing? I'm taking a piss, asshole!
你干嘛？我还没完呢，混球！
- Yeah. - Yo!
- 那是 - 唷！
I'm not joining the mile-high club with you.
我可不跟你玩儿高空激情
What about the really high club?
那真正的激情要不要？
- Are you retarded? - No.
- 你脑子进屎了？ - 不行
You brought weed on the fucking airplane?
你丫把大麻带飞机上来了？
- Yep. - What the fuck?
- 对呀 - 搞什么飞机？
Wait a second. You were giving that security guard shit.
原来如此，你是故意在安检那儿找茬的
Yeah. How else was I supposed to get past him?
当然，不然怎么过得来？
By not bringing drugs on an airplane?
那就不带毒品上飞机？
- Look... What are you doing? What is this? - You'll see.
- 等…你要干嘛？这是什么？ - 等着瞧
Harold Lee, I would like to introduce you to an invention of mine.
哈罗德・李，现在向你展示我的最新发明
Meet the smokeless bong.
请看无烟烟枪
- You made this? - You know, I did.
- 你弄出来的？ - 你看见了
When you were slaving away at work...
你还在拚命打工的时候
I was actually being a productive member of society.
本人就已产值颇丰了
- Yeah, that's really productive. - Let me show you how it works.
- 是啊，是够丰富的 - 我给你演示怎么操作
So you take a little weed...
拿一小撮大麻
put it in the bowl right here and light it just like a normal bong, OK?
放进这个烟管，然后点燃 跟普通烟枪没什么两样，对吧？
Now here's the truly genius part.
马上就是高明之处了
Inside this mechanism, I have actually made a little tiny, tiny fan...
在这机器内部，我做了一个非常非常微小的风扇
and some disinfectant powder, OK, it works sort of like a deodorizer...
还有一点消毒粉，工作原理跟除臭剂有点像
so that anything it expunges smells like Lysol.
这样就只有类似莱尔沙（一种消毒剂）的味道了
- Put it away. - No, dude.
- 收起来 - 不，兄弟
Can you not wait till we get to Amsterdam?
你就不能等到阿姆斯特丹再说？
It's the weed capital of the world!
那可是全球烟草之都！
- No. - Put the bong away!
- 不行 - 烟枪收起来！
- Take the inaugural hit, dude. - No!
- 尝一下这东西的第一口，哥们 - 不行！
Come on, man.
没事的
- Then I'm gonna do it. - Put it away. Put the frickin' bong away.
- 就这样了 - 收起来，把该死的烟枪收起来
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Turb...
抱歉，不好意思，乱流…
Terrorist!
恐怖分子！
Roldy?
罗迪？
- What the fuck is that thing in his hands? - No, ma'am, not a terrorist.
- 他拿了个什么东西？ - 不，女士，不是恐怖分子
- He's just an idiot. - This is just a bong.
- 他不过是在犯傻 - 这是装大麻的枪
He said he got a bomb!
他说那是装弹药的腔！
No, people, it's a water pipe for tobacco.
不是，各位，那是个吸烟的水管
No, no, no, it's not a bomb. It's just a bong.
不不不，不是炸弹，是烟枪
Poison gas!
毒气！
It's marijuana! Marijuana!
是大麻！大麻！
You picked the wrong plane, you terrorist fuck!
恐怖粪子，你们上错飞机了！
Hey! Hey, what are you doing?
嘿！嘿，你干嘛？
There are three air marshals on board. Three!
机上有三名中将，三名！
We are not terrorists! Sir, that's a bong, not a bomb.
我们不是恐怖分子，先生，那是烟枪不是炸弹
Shut up!
闭嘴！
I got this one!
我抓到这个了！
- Roldy? - Please don't!
- 罗迪? - 别！
I am in a great amount of pain!
疼死我了！
Everybody relax. Just calm down. Everything is under control.
大家别慌，镇静，已经没事了
Tell 'em to turn the plane around. These two assholes are goin' back to the U.S.
让他们把飞机开回去，这两个混球得滚回美国
Secretary Fox. Glad you could make it.
福克斯部长，很高兴由您接手
Think I'd miss a terrorist attack of this magnitude?
以为我会放任这些小打小闹？
Not a fuckin' chance.
没门
Who are these people?
他们是什么人？
Representatives of the different intelligence agencies.
各分属情报部门的代表
I assume Secretary Whitmore's coming?
我想，维特摩尔部长会过来吧？
Negative. He's on an ice fishing trip in Glacier Bay.
不会，他正在冰河湾冰钓
I'm in charge while he's gone.
此间由我来接替他的工作
Well, shouldn't he be alerted?
那么，不需要通知到他本人么？
Isn't this issue of more importance than an ice fishing trip?
难道此事不比冰钓之重？
Who are you again?
你是谁来着？
Dr. John Beecher, Vice Chairman of the NSA.
约翰・比彻博士，国安局副主席
Yeah, well, listen, dr... dipshit.
是啊，那么听着，白痴博士
You've obviously never been ice fishing before.
显然你是没有冰钓的经历了
- No, I haven't. - Yeah, well, it's fucking exhilarating.
- 不，我没有 - 告诉你，可他妈爽着呢
The last thing anyone would want while fishing for pike is to be interrupted.
在捕狗鱼的人最痛恨的就是被打搅
Now back off...
闪一边去
and let me do my job.
别耽误我开工
What's up with the guy with the weird eyes?
那家伙眼睛怎么弄得怪怪的？
He handicapped or something?
残疾还是怎么了？
We believe he's of Korean descent.
我们推断他是韩裔
My God.
上帝啊
North Korea and al-Qaeda workin' together.
朝鲜和基地组织联合作战了啊
This is bigger than I thought.
比我想得还猛
You couldn't wait?
等不了？
You couldn't fucking wait?
你他妈等不了了？
We were about to have all the legal weed we wanted.
本来能尽情合法地享用大麻
You know, in Amsterdam, where we were going!
你也知道，因为是阿姆斯特丹，我们的目的地！
Thought you could get away with this, huh?
以为能蒙混过关，啊？
You thought that after 9/11 our national security was a joke, huh?
你们以为，911之后，国家安全就成了笑柄了？
Well...
好
guess what?
猜怎么着？
What?
怎么？
We knew you fuckers would be back.
我们知道你们这些杂种会再来的
- Holy shit! - But we're Americans, man.
- 妈呀！ - 我们是美国人，大哥
- We love America. We love America! - Very much.
- 我们爱美国，我们热爱美国！ - 非常热爱
That's a convenient thing to say...
你们试图炸了一个载满美国人的飞机
after you try and blow up a plane filled with Americans!
还大言不惭的说热爱！
- No. - No, we didn't do...
- 没有 - 不，我们没有…
No, you see, you have the wrong idea.
不，您看，您误会了
My idiot friend here brought marijuana...
我这个傻哥们带了点儿大麻
- on the plane. - Yeah, hey, hey, hey, hey.
- 上了飞机 - 对，喂，喂，喂，喂
Zip it, Hello Kitty. OK? I know your operation's funded through drugs.
闭嘴，基蒂猫，乖？ 我知道你们的组织基金靠毒品交易
No. This is typical government bullshit, sir. L...
不，这是典型官方屁话，先生，我…
- Hey, hey, hey. Shut up. Shut up! - L...
- 嘿，嘿，嘿，闭嘴，闭嘴！ - 我...
- No, I'm trying to explain it! Harold! - Shut up, shut up, shut up! Shut up!
- 我在想办法解释清楚！ 哈罗德！ - 闭嘴，闭嘴，闭嘴，闭嘴！
Do we have the right to make a phone call?
我们有权打个电话么？
Yeah. Yeah!
是啊，对啊！
I'm sorry. You want rights now.
不好意思，你们要权利是吧
You want freedoms right now.
你们要自由权
Is it time? Is it freedom o'clock?
到时候了？现在是自由时刻了？
- Guess what. - What?
- 猜怎么着？ - 怎么？
Where you guys are going, they have never even heard of rights.
你们要去的地方，不存在权利一说
Well, where are we going?
我们要去哪里？
We're innocent men!
我们是清白的！我们是清白的！
I'm an innocent man.
我是个清白的人
I donate blood.
我献血
And toys for tots.
给小孩儿捐玩具
And now I'm in Guantanamo Bay.
却被关在关塔那摩湾
See why I'm against paying taxes?
明白我为什么抗税了吧？
Hey! Hey.
嘿！嘿
Fuck you!
滚蛋吧你！
Dude, calm down, OK?
兄弟，别激动，好吧？
Look on the bright side. There's a sink. There's a toilet.
看开点儿，有水池，有马桶
The pillow actually looks pretty comfortable.
枕头也挺舒服
OK. You don't speak to me, ever.
好了，你再也别和我说话了
- Ever. - OK.
- 永远 - 好啊
- No! Shut up!
- 不行！闭嘴！ - 好
So what are you guys in here for?
你们怎么进来的？
For giving the United States a taste of their own medicine.
因为让美国尝到了他们自己的药剂
- You guys are real terrorists? - Some call us terrorists.
- 你们是真正的恐怖分子？ - 有人称我们为恐怖分子
Others call us heroes.
其他人，视我们为英雄
Screw that. You think you guys are heroes for killing innocent people?
扯淡，你们这帮家伙伤害无辜就英雄了？
It's 'cause of assholes like you that we're even in this fucking place...
都是你们这帮混蛋我们才落到这步田地的
you fucking cowards!
你们这些胆小鬼！
Well, maybe if the people in your country stopped eating donuts...
要是你们国家的人民不再吃甜甜圈
and started realizing what your government is doing to the world...
还能看清你们的政府在世上的所做所为
assholes like us wouldn't exist.
压根就不会有我们这样的混蛋了
- Fuck you! Donuts are awesome! - They're delicious.
- 玩儿去吧你！甜甜圈香甜可口！ - 味道好极了
You like donuts?
你们喜欢甜甜圈？
Well, wait till you see what they make you eat in here.
那就期待着他们给你们吃什么吧
- Yeah? - What do they make you eat in here?
- 怎样？ - 他们给你们吃什么？
L...
比...
Ever hear of a cockmeat sandwich?
听过鸡蛋饼么？
What's a cockmeat sandwich?
什么是鸡蛋饼
You're about to find out.
你们即将品尝到
Right about now. Sucker.
马上奉上，白痴
All right, cockmeat sandwich time. You know the drill.
好了，鸡蛋饼来了，你们知道规矩
What about them? They just got here!
怎么不找他们？他们也进来了！
Big Bob's taking care of them.
大勃来照顾他们
- Big Bob. - Big Bob?
- 大勃？
I hope you like donuts.
希望你们喜欢甜甜圈
Let's go to work. Hey, listen, guys, enjoy.
咱们开工吧，嘿，你们就等着享受吧
Holy shit.
我的神啊
Oh, yeah, that's it.
哦，耶，就这样
- This is not good. - No, Kumar, it is not good.
- 这下惨了 - 对，库马，这下惨了
- I've never had to suck a dick before. - Me neither.
- 我从没干过这活儿 - 我也没有
I bet it sucks dick.
肯定是吹箫
Shit, dude.
完了，兄弟
Please don't let it be Big Bob.
千万别是大勃，千万别是大勃
Come on.
千万别是大勃，拜托
- Please don't let it be Big Bob. - I'm Big Bob.
- 千万别是大勃 - 我是大勃
- Fuck. - Yes, you are.
- 靠 - 看出来了
You boys ready for your cockmeat sandwich?
你们准备好享用鸡蛋饼了么？
No?
还没？
Well, you better get hungry real fast...
那你们最好马上消化
'cause I got a whole lot of sandwich waitin' for ya.
因为我为你们准备了丰盛的蛋饼
Holy shit!
救命！
- All right, let's get goin'. - Hold on, hold on, hold on, Big Bob...
- 好了，开始吧 - 等等，等等，大勃
I got to ask you a question before this all goes down.
在开始之前有个问题我不吐不快
- All the guards in Guantanamo are gay? - Fuck, no!
- 关塔那摩的警卫都是男同志么？ - 操，不是！
Ain't nothing gay about getting your dick sucked!
男同志才不会让你给他吹箫！
You're the ones that's gay for suckin' my dick!
你们吹的人才是男同志！
- What? - In fact...
- 什么？ - 其实
creeps me out just bein' around you fags.
跟你们这些断背男在一起老子还恶心呢
- But... - All right.
- 可… - 行了
- Wait... - Get down on your knees...
- 等… - 快跪下吧…
- and open your mouths. - Please, Big Bob.
- 把嘴巴张开 - 求你了，大勃
Why don't you just kick our ass instead?
改踢屁屁不行么？
- Get on your fucking knees! - All right. All right.
- 给我跪下！ - 好的好的
- All right, all right, all right, all right. - You go first, dude.
- 好好好好 - 你先来，哥们
Hope you boys like extra mayo.
希望二位喜欢极品蛋黄酱
- Jesus, Kumar. - Oh, I hate you so much!
- 天啊， 库马 - 我恨死你了！
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不住，对不住啊
God, his dick smells like shit, dude.
天啊，他的老二跟屎一个味儿
Holy shit!
老天爷啊！
- What the hell happened? - That terrorist fuck bit my dick!
- 这是怎么了？ - 恐怖分子咬我老二！
- Come on. - Wait, wait, wait, wait a second!
- 快走 - 等等，等一下！
Should we? What if they kill us out there?
要走吗？跑出去被他们毙了怎么办？
They're gonna fucking make us suck their dicks if we don't.
不跑就他妈得给他们吹箫
We're gonna die in here. Come on.
那还不如死了，快走吧
- Fuck. Fuck. - Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
- 操，操 - 我靠，我靠
- Shit. Shit. - Fuck. Fuck.
- 靠，靠 - 操，操
- Oh, shit! Get out! - Fuck!
- 我靠，快跑！ - 操！
Oh, shit. Shit.
哦，靠，靠
Door, door.
门，门
Look, look, look.
快看，看，看
What the fuck is he doing?
他要干嘛？
We've got to go now, now, now, now, now!
咱们得快走了，快走快走！
It smells like burnt asshole.
好大的焦臭
I can't fucking believe this.
怎么会这样
Fuck!
操！
My wrist is swelling, man!
我的手腕肿了，天啊！
- Shut up. - We're gonna die in a jungle!
- 闭嘴 - 咱们会死在树林里的！
- Shut up! - Fuck!
- 操！
Watch out for cheetahs! This is cheetah turf.
小心猎豹，这是它们的地盘
- What? - OK. Fuck.
- 什么？ - 好了，他娘的
We hit ocean. What do we do now?
到海边了，怎么办？
All right.
没事
Hey, look, look!
嘿，看，看啊！
Excuse me.
打扰了
You guys going to America?
你们是去美国么？
Yes, we're going.
是啊，我们就出发了
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm telling you, Jorge...
告诉你，乔治…
the first thing you have to do when you get to America...
到了美国第一件事…
buy a device called TiVo, OK?
就是买一个叫电视的东西，知道吗？
Freedom means nothing if you're a slave to regular programming...
如果你让电视节目拴住了，自由就狗屁不是了
I promise you that.
我不骗你
And now, how about you focus?
到这份儿上你还有心闲扯？
We gotta figure out what to do when we get to the States.
到美国之前咱们必须想出办法
We don't have wallets. We don't have any Id. We've got nothing.
咱们身无分文，无名无份
Well, I figure we're gonna land somewhere around Miami, right?
咱们差不多该在迈阿密附近靠岸
There's only one guy we know who lives down there.
那就只有这一个熟人了
- Who do we know that... Raza. - Yeah.
- 我们认识…拉扎. - 对
We gotta go see Raza.
咱们得去他那看看
- Thanks again. - What nice people.
- 谢谢了 - 多好的人呐
Man, South Florida here we are.
哥们，咱们终于到南佛罗里达了
OK. So, now how do we get to Raza's?
先别美，怎么去拉扎家？
The professional way. We walk. Let's go.
行家之选，步行，来吧
- Walk? - Yeah.
- 走着？ - 对啊
So I guess Raza's...
拉扎家在…
- We'll find it, we'll find it. ...thataway. Yeah.
- 找得到的，一定找得到 ...这个方向，没错
- Wow, Raza's place is pretty sweet. - Kinda ghetto for Miami.
- 哇,，拉扎这里还真是气派 - 这在迈阿密算穷的
- Hi. - Hey.
- 嗨
Y'all aren't here to complain about the noise, are you?
你们不是嫌太吵吧，对么？
No. We're not... here to complain about the noise.
不，我们不是…来投诉你们的
We're...
我们是…
We are here to see...
我们来找人…
- What is his name? We're here... - Vagina.
- 他叫什么来着？我们是来… - 阴部
No, we're here to see Raza.
不是，我们是来找拉扎的
OK. Follow me.
好啊，跟我来
Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢，女士
We'll follow... you, I guess.
我们当然…跟着你
Hey.
嗨
- Very patriotic of you. - Thank you.
- 够爱国的 - 多谢夸奖
- Hey, guys. - Hey.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey, Raza! - What?
- 嘿，拉扎！ - 不是吧？
What's up?
好久不见？
- Kumar and Roldy? - What's up, man?
- 库马和罗迪？ - 怎么样啊，你们？
I haven't seen you guys since graduation.
毕业后都没碰过面
What are you guys doing here?
什么风把你们给吹来了？
Wait, what's up with the orange jumpsuits?
等等，你们穿成这样干嘛？
- Hey, no, no, question number one... - It's kind of a long story. L...
- 嘿，不不，第一个问题… - 说来话长了…
...what's up with this party? - What do you mean?
你这个派队是怎么回事？ - 有何不妥？
There's exposed vagina all over your house.
到处都是赤裸下体
Yeah. That was my idea.
是啊，我想的点子
I don't know about you guys, I'm sick of all the hype over topless.
不知你们怎样，我是看腻了上半身
Really? I always liked toplessness. That's...
真的？我一直喜欢上半部分，不过…
- That's just me. - Yeah? Well, I'm starting...
- 我是这样的 - 这样？我想…
the bottomless trend. Hence, the bottomless party.
引领下空风潮，所以有了这个下空派对
So what are you guys doing in South Beach?
你们跑来南方海滩干什么？
How about you answer that question? I'm gonna go check this out.
你来说好吧？我到这边看看
- Where are you going? - Bang bang, buddy.
- 你上哪去？ - 玩一玩，哥们
Listen. I'm really sorry to bother you with this.
兄弟，这事挺难开口
- You all right? - Not really.
- 你没事吧？ - 事大了
They were locked up for less than an hour, and they already escaped?
关起来一个小时不到就跑了？
Damn it. Make sure the press doesn't get wind of this.
妈的，别走漏风声让媒体逮到
Don't need the public thinking we're some two-bit operation.
用不着让公众把我们当无能来批
Got it, sir.
明白，长官
It must have been either al-Qaeda or North Korea who broke 'em up.
不是基地就是朝鲜把他们弄出去的
Find out if they have any relatives in the country.
查查他们在这些地方的亲戚
You probably should have done that in the first place.
这些工作早该完成了
Do you have a problem with the way I'm running the show, Beecher?
你对我的玩儿法有意见吗，比彻？
I'm just saying that...
我不过是想提醒一下…
I've looked through the files on Harold Lee and Kumar Patel.
我已经查过二人的资料
They were both born and raised in New Jersey.
他们都是新泽西土生土长的人
Other than a couple of traffic tickets, they're clean.
除了几个交通罚单，底子很干净
Right. That's why they just broke out of prison.
对，这就是他们越狱的最佳解释了
But they... lt's not even clear that they should have been there in the first place.
可他们…一开始把他们送到那里就不够明确
Shut your...
闭上你的…
You see this cute, little white girl, Beecher?
看到这个可爱的白人小女孩儿了么，比彻？
Yeah.
怎么
Do you want her to get raped and murdered?
你愿意她被奸杀么？
Of course not.
当然不
You sure? 'Cause this is America.
确定？这可是美国
- Do you want to rape America? - No.
- 你要强奸美国么？ - 不
Then stop fucking with me.
那就别再搞我
This is serious.
小心点
She's adorable.
小丫头蛮可爱
So you guys are fucking fugitives?
你俩现在是亡命徒了？
It's just it's Kumar's fault.
都是库马惹的祸
If we get out of this...
要是能逃此劫…
the chances of us remaining friends is highly...
我们还能做朋友的几率就大大…
highly... boobies. Yeah.
大大的…咪咪，啊
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
嘿，你这是干什么？
Put that back on. And keep it on.
穿上，不许脱下来
- Sorry. - Fuckin' party do you think this is?
- 抱歉 - 把我这当成什么聚会了？
Yo. What are you guys talking about?
唷，你们聊什么呢？
Roldy was just letting me in on your situation.
罗迪正把你的烂摊子推给我
- Yeah? - Thanks for getting me involved.
- 是吗？ - 多谢你们还想着我
What about that fuckin' time we had to cover for you...
怎么不提我们帮你撒谎骗你前女友…
lie to your ex-girlfriend about how you got crabs?
隐瞒你的虱病那事？
You owe us, man.
你欠我们人情呢
- Yeah, that's right. - What?
- 是啊，没错 - 什么？
- OK, that was a long time ago. - I love crabs.
- 行了，陈年旧事 - 我喜欢阴虱
Speaking of ex-girlfriends...
说到前女友…
isn't yours getting married or something?
你那位不是要结婚了么？
How does everybody know about this except for me?
怎么大家都知道就我还蒙在鼓里？
Wait.
等等
Colton! Colton Graham can help us out.
克尔顿！克尔顿・格雷厄姆能帮上忙
- No! Fuck that! - Yes!
- 不行！去他娘的！ - 行！
No doubt. If anyone could clear your names, it's him.
没错，这事能帮你们洗底的，就只有他了
No, I'm sorry. That dickweed is not helping us.
不行，这个操蛋家伙不会帮咱们的
Wait a second. Do you have his contact info?
对了，你有他的联系方式么？
Not anymore. But the wedding is at his family's estate in Hewitt, Texas.
现在没了，不过他们 要在德州翰威特的家族官邸举办婚礼
But you don't want to bother them when they're doing their whole...
你们不会在人家举行婚礼的时候…
wedding thing, right?
跑去败兴吧？
You know, that actually might be our only hope.
说真的，这可能是最后一跟救命草了
Fuck! How do we get there? We can't go to the airport. They're looking for us.
我靠！我们该怎么去啊？又不能登机 他们在追查我们！
- I'll loan you one of my cars. - Really?
- 我借你们一辆车 - 真的？
But first... y'all got to get in the spirit of the party.
但是首先…你们得对派对精神身体力行
- What do you mean, spirit of... - What do you think I mean?
- 你指力行什么… - 还用说吗？
- What about you? - Me? I've been in the spirit.
- 你自己呢？ - 我？我在演绎派对精神啊
- Oh, God! - Oh, my God, dude!
- 噢，天啊！ - 噢，老天啊，哥们！
Oh, my God!
上帝啊！
- Love your dickdo, Raza. - Yeah. Drink it in.
- 爱你的个性小弟，拉扎. - 没错，来吧
- What the fuck? - That looks like Osama bin Laden's beard.
- 那他妈是怎么回事？ - 怎么跟本・拉登的胡子一样
I know, right? All right, boys.
我故意的，怎样？好了，兄弟们
Your turn. Let 'em dangle.
该你们了，甩起来吧
- Let's just do it. - Bring it.
- 不然就脱吧 - 亮出来
Count of three?
数到三？
One.
一
Two, three.
二，三
Your cocks are awesome, man!
你的家伙很拉风啊！
That's not even necessary.
犯不着幅度那么大吧
- Would you please... - Oh, my dick!
- 你能不能… - 噢我的枪！
#My dick cost a late-night fee #
#我的家伙得收过夜费#
#Your dick got the HIV #
#你的家伙却有HIV（艾滋病毒）#
#My dick plays on the double feature screen #
#我的家伙表演分上下集#
#Your dick went straight to dVd #
#你的家伙直接出dVd#
#My dick bigger than a bridge #
#我的家伙能跨一条河 #
#Your dick look like a little kid's #
#你的家伙短到惹人乐#
#My dick large like the Chargers, the whole team #
#我的家伙像杆冲锋枪，率领全队 #
#Your shit look like you 14 #
#你那一坨像男童未满14岁#
#My dick locked in a cage, right #
#我的家伙犹如困兽犹斗#
#Your dick suffer from stage fright #
#你的家伙还没上就泄漏#
#My dick so hot it's stolen #
#我的家伙热拉风热辣#
#Your dick look like Gary Coleman #
#你的家伙好似矮冬瓜#
#My dick pink and big #
#我的家伙形美色正#
- This car is frickin' sweet. - Yeah, yeah, it's sweet.
- 这车超正点 - 没错，没错，够正
'Cause we're fugitives.
尤其对于亡命徒来说
Driving a yellow convertible with the top down, dressed like assholes!
开着黄色敞篷跑车，穿得如此扎眼！
Yo. Yo. Yo, look, he has one of these things.
唷，唷，看，他还有这东西
- Would you put that down? - No, you can hook up to the Internet.
- 你赶紧放回去行吗？ - 才不，还能上网
You can play M/ke Tyson's Punch-Out// on it. King Hippo's going down.
还能《拳击》，河马王被击倒
Put that away. Put that away.
放回去，放回去
I can't believe you can even think about playing games at a time like this, man.
都这时候了你还有心思玩游戏，佩服
You realize what would happen if our parents found out about this?
要是你爹妈知道了该怎么办？
You have sent our sons to Guantanamo Bay?
你把我们的儿子送到关塔那摩湾去了？
This is an outrage!
凭什么这么做！
You Arabs think you can just mix in with our peaceful society...
你以为你们阿拉伯人能融入我们和谐的社会…
and we're not gonna find you, huh?
然后逃出我们的法眼，是吧？
I am not Arab! I am Indian!
我不是阿拉伯人，我是印度人
Look, Chief. I'm not here to argue seblantics with you, OK?
听着，长官，今天不是来讨论这个的，懂吗？
I'm here to save lives.
我的任务是挽救生命
Ask the Lees what they know about their son's terrorist activity.
问问姓李的对他们儿子的恐怖活动知道多少
Look, we have been American citizens for over 40 years.
听着，我们已经身为美国公民40余年
Now, frankly, I find this very offensive.
直说吧，这种行为是严重的冒犯
They're using some sort of dialect I've never heard before.
他们说话的口音我还真没听过
But I'm pretty sure he said something about going on the offensive.
但我敢保证他们在说冒犯方面的事
Tell them we know what their son is up to...
告诉他们我们知道他们的儿子去哪儿了
and if they don't cooperate, he could be sentenced to death.
要是他们不合作，他就会被判处死刑
Hit 'em. Yeah.
吓吓他们，说
We know what he said!
我们听得懂！
Sir, Harold and Kumar are good boys.
先生，哈罗德都是库马好孩子
I'm a pretty good translator.
我是比较优秀的翻译
It's total gibberish.
他们在胡说八道
They may be trying to stonewall us.
他们是想干扰我们
Are you sure you speak Korean, Jack?
你确定自己说的是韩语，杰克？
You speak Korean?
你会说韩语？
You're not fucking with daddy, are you?
你没耍你老子吧？
Do you have a masters in romantic Korean literature?
你有韩国浪漫文学硕士学位么？
Because I do...
因为本人有…
and I'm offended.
所以你别多事
Good enough for me.
那最好
Look, excuse me...
请原谅…
we're not looking to hurt your sons...
我们并不是要伤害你们的孩子…
we just wanna know where they are.
只是想尽快找到他们
Do you know if they know anybody in Florida?
他们在佛罗里达有没有什么熟人？
Their friend Raza Syed lives in Miami.
他们的朋友拉扎・希德在迈阿密
But why would they be there?
可他们怎么回去那里？
He's supposed to be in medical school.
他该在医学院才对
They are supposed to be in prison! That is where terrorists belong!
他们该在监狱！恐怖分子就该待在牢里！
These fuckers are goin' down.
造乱者终将落网
Dead. Or alive.
击毙，或活捉
Tell them that in your fake ching-chong language.
用你那粤腔告诉他们
Shut up! You're an idiot.
闭嘴！你个白痴！
I don't know what you're saying, buddy...
虽然不懂你的话，伙计
but fuck you.
但我操你
- Fuck me? - Will you let him talk to you like that?
- 操我？ - 你就让他这么侮辱你？
- Listen, no, sit down. - Fuck me?
- 别了，不要，坐下 - 操我？
Hey, look, man, we're in Alabama.
嘿，咱们都到阿拉巴马了
Wow, we actually get a first-hand look at the South, huh?
哇，我们还是头一回来南方呢，对吧？
Hey, this wasn't supposed to be a trip through the South, OK?
拜托你，我们不是来旅游的，好不好？
This was supposed to be the most romantic week of my life.
本该是我人生中最浪漫的一周
Remember that? Before you fucked it up? You remember that?
还记得吗？被你搅和之前？想起来了么？
Just chill, OK? We'll be out of this situation.
别这么火大，行吧？咱们会没事的
You'll be up in Maria's guts in no time, all right?
不用过多久你就能进玛丽亚的肠子了，好吧？
Hey. She's not some skank, man.
住口，她不是乱交的人
I've never felt this way about anyone before, really.
我从来没有过现在这种感觉，真的
What the fuck? Why am I talking to you about this?
我他妈怎么了？和你说这个干嘛？
It's not like you would understand, so...
对牛弹琴，真是…
Excuse me, please. Will you turn that off? This is a library.
我说，拜托，你能关掉吗？这可是图书馆
What a fucking chode.
这哥们够蠢蛋
Thank you, come again!
多谢，欢迎再来！
- What the fuck?! - Oh, my God.
- 怎么搞得？！ - 噢，老天啊
You know, the whole reason people come to the stacks...
同学，到这里来的目的
is for some peace and...
就是求份安宁和
quiet.
肃静
Look, I know, I'm sorry. I hate it when people disturb me here too.
我也知道，抱歉，别人打断我我也会火大
It's just this fucking calculus final is killing me.
都是这倒霉的数学期末考快气死人了
- Do you mind if I take a look? - No.
- 介意我帮你看看么 - 不会
- You're actually very close. May I? - Yeah.
- 你就快算出来了，能不能？ - 没事
Excuse me.
见谅
I touched your breast.
我碰到你胸部了
- It's OK. - Sorry.
- 没事的 - 不好意思
You just go...
你这么做…
Wow. You're good at this.
哇，你挺强的嘛
Thanks.
谢谢
What did you, like, take calculus in high school or something?
你怎么学的，是不是高中就会微积分了？
Actually, my dad taught it to me in sixth grade.
其实，我爸六年级就教我微积分了
What, are you like doogie Howser?
你也是“天才小医生”那种孩子吗？
No. Although that would be incredible. He's my hero.
不，尽管确实挺超乎寻常的，他可是我的偶像
I love that show.
我喜欢那个电视剧
What are you working on there?
你在这看什么？
This is just a poem for my creative writing class.
这是我写作课创作的一首小诗
It's like...
就像...
- "The Square Root Of Three"? - No, no, I'm sorry...
- “三的平方根”？ - 不不，抱歉…
- "A poem of love by Kumar Patel." - I need this.
- "爱之诗，库玛・巴特尔" - 还给我
- Hey, let me read it. - No, no.
- 让我读一读 - 不行
- Why? - Because it's lame.
- 为什么？ - 写得很菜
Then read it to me.
读了再评判
There's no way I'm letting you see me in that light. Good luck with your calculus.
绝对不能让你把我想歪了 好好研究你的微积分吧
Come on, don't be embarrassed. You know, a lot of girls find intelligence sexy.
得了，别不好意思了，女孩都喜欢聪明的男人
Look, I'm not even gonna be showing this to my professor, all right?
真的，这东西我都不会给我教授看的 明白么？
That's why I'm so stressed out right now.
所以我才这么暴躁
Stressed out, huh?
暴躁，对吗？
Come with me.
过来
...going? - Come on.
出去？ - 来吧
What?
干嘛？
You're smoking drugs in the library? What if somebody catches us?
你带这个进图书馆？被人发现怎么办？
Don't worry. It'll help you relax.
别紧张嘛，轻松一下
Oh, boy.
天呀
It's illegal.
这是违禁的
Here.
来
This is poison.
简直是毒药
Let me help you.
我来教你玩儿
I'm Kumar.
我叫库马
Vanessa.
瓦内萨
You're still not reading that poem.
你还没读诗呢
Kumar.
库马
Kumar. Kumar.
库马，库马
- Kumar. - Yeah.
- 库马 - 啊
What's going on? We're in Birmingham, Alabama. Are we supposed to be here?
干嘛呢你？咱们到阿拉巴马的伯明翰了 是走这边么？
What's going on?
怎么回事？
- Why did you bring us here, dude? - What do you mean, why did l...
- 你怎么开到这儿了？ - 你什么意思，我怎么…
You were supposed to be following the directions, asshole. What do you mean?
你负责看地图的，混蛋，你怎么搞的？
There's got to be like a highway or something, right?
到这里应该有条大道的，对吧？
Yeah, there's got to be a highway.
没错，是该有条大道
What's going on up there?
前面干什么呢？
What the hell is this?
这是搞什么？
- I'm turning around. - Nah, just go through, man.
- 得调头 - 别，开过去吧，没事
Dude, we're not driving through this basketball game.
我说，从球场上开过去是找死
You know, Roldy, I really thought you were bigger than this.
我认为，你比他们更彪悍
Dude, I'm not scared 'cause they're black.
兄弟，我不是因为他们是黑人才怕
I'm scared because they're scary.
我怕是因为他们长得很骇人
And it's not like we got Gregory Hines out there.
他们可不是什么格雷戈里・海因斯（踢踏舞王）
They're not that scary.
他们都是狠角色
It's my ball!
球是我的！
Turn around.
调头
- Fuck! It won't move! - Shit, dude.
- 干！开不起来了！ - 惨了，哥们
- That's not good. - Now there's no music, man.
- 完了 - 音乐都停了
Shit, man.
该死，伙计
- Motherfucker! - My Jordans, nigga!
- 妈的混蛋！ - 我的乔丹鞋，老兄！
- Shit, this isn't good. - This is not good. This is not good.
- 惨了，这下不好了 - 完了，完了
No. No. No.
别，别，别
They're coming over here.
他们过来了
- Fucking shit. Why did you do that? - Yeah, I hit a fire hydrant on purpose.
- 妈的，该死，你搞什么啊？ - 对，我故意往消防栓上撞
They're getting weapons, man.
他们操家伙了，伙计
All right, what do we do? What do we do?
好好，我们怎么办？怎么办？
Run, run, run. Run, run.
跑，快跑，快
Yo. Yo.
唷，嘿
- Where y'all going? Damn! - We was just trying to help.
- 你们怎么跑了？妈的！ - 我们是来帮忙的
Man, somebody call the police. We need to report this.
我看咱们报警吧，情况可疑
- Yeah, that's right. You like the ride? - Fuck you, man.
- 嘿，好吧，喜欢那车么？ - 滚吧你
They abandoned it last night. It's registered to a Raza Syed.
他们昨晚把车丢在这的，车主是拉扎・希德
The witnesses' description of the driver and passenger...
根据证人描述，司机和乘客
match that of Lee and Patel.
同李和巴特尔特征吻合
We tried bringing in Syed last night, but he's already left the country.
昨晚我们想把希德带过来的，可他已经出国了
Well, they know we're closing in on 'em, that's why.
他心里有鬼才跑路的
OK. No, I'll give you a call. All right.
行，不用，我给你回电话，好了
No, no, no, no!
别别别！
- Holy shit! - Easy, easy!
- 见鬼了！ - 别慌，别慌！
- Easy. - Easy!
- 别紧张 - 冷静！
This is our witness.
这是我们的证人
Put it down! Yo, put it down!
放下！唷，放下！
So, you saw the fugitives, huh?
那你看见那两个逃犯了？
Yeah. It was like I was telling the Sheriff...
对啊，我已经和警官说了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. How do I know you're telling the truth?
对啊，对啊，对啊，对啊，对啊 谁知道你说的是真是假？
I don't have a reason to lie to you, man.
我没理由撒谎
Really?
是嘛？
- Get up in your face, man. - We'll see.
咱们开证实一下
Where's he going?
他干嘛去了？
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Hell no!
可恶！
Now why don't you tell me what really happened?
乖乖地说实话吧？
Is that grape soda?
是葡萄汽水（俚语中有污辱的意思）吗？
What the fuck, yo?
他搞什么？
- All right. - Hold on, hold on, hold on!
- 好啦 - 慢着，慢着，慢着！
This is so ignorant.
这样就没素质了
- Really? - Yes.
- 会吗？ - 确实
Is this ignorant?
没素质？
Yo, that's racist, man. That's racist.
嘿，这家伙种族歧视，他是个偏见分子！
Hey, Jon, are you gonna let him do that?
嘿，乔恩，你放任他不管？
See if he got Kool-Aid.
看看他有没有料
Almost gone, witness.
快完了，目击者
Sure there's not something you wanna tell me?
还是没什么要跟我交代的吗？
I'm not stoppin' until you crack!
你不开口老子不会罢休的！
I already told you that they took off runnin'!
我都说了他们逃跑了！
All right, all right, all right.
好了好了好了
This isn't necessary! Mr. White is telling you the truth!
没必要这么搞！怀特先生所言属实！
Yeah, and how can you be so sure, Beecher?
是吗？你怎么这么清楚，比扯？
'Cause he doesn't have a police record. He's an orthodontist, for Christ's sake.
因为他是一位正直的正牙师，无犯罪记录，拜托
OK, then, Beech. How do you propose we find the terrorists, huh?
好呀，比彻，那你倒说说 我们该如何追查这些恐怖分子？
There was a Nokia 7710 taken from the console.
机座上有部诺基亚7710不见了
We have its tracking numbers.
我们可以追踪号码
Our satellites are running a trace on it, as we speak.
通话的时候卫星可以跟踪信号
What's going on? Where are you?
还好吧？你们到哪了？
Dude, that is a fucking long story.
哥们，说来话长
We're actually in Alabama right now, heading to Texas.
我们现在到阿拉巴马了，正往德州去
What is that sound? Are you jerking off again? What are you doing?
什么动静？你又打飞机呢？干嘛呢？
I'm taking a glorious pee-pee.
尿得太爽了
Hey, listen, you're not gonna believe this...
对了，我和说个好玩儿的…
but the other night, I ended up at that Asian party...
前几天晚上我从一个亚裔派对上回来
and I schtupped Cindy Kim.
我搞了辛蒂・金
Shut the fuck up. Are you serious?
少来了，瞎说的吧？
Yeah, man, she even gave me a blumpkin.
真的，她还给我吹拉
What is a blumpkin?
什么是吹拉？
It's when a girl gives you head while you're sitting on the toilet takin' a shit.
就是你坐那拉屎的时候有姑娘给你吹箫
Really?
我靠？
- Hello? - Hey. Hey! What are you doing?
- 喂？ - 嘿，嘿！你这是干嘛？
Hello? Come, come?
喂？在吗？
Did you go?
好了吗？
Yeah, I'm done.
完事了
You said to me we were gonna cross swords. You promised.
说好了咱们一起拼剑的，你答应的
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
好了，甜心
Are you talking on a cellphone when the government is looking for us?
政府正满世界找我们，你还打手机？
Dude, it was just Goldstein. I had something important to tell him.
没有，我打给古德斯坦因，有要紧的事和他商量
It's 'cause you had something... That's good, that's OK.
原来是要紧的事…那好，没事了
Nothing is more important than finding a way to get to Texas.
没有任何事，比想办法到德州更要紧
- Do you get it? - Yes.
- 听懂了吗？ - 懂了
We've been walking an entire day and we have not seen a street sign.
都走了一整天都没见一个路标
Do you get it?
你还不知死活吗？
- Can I say... - Again. This is... I can't.
- 我想说… - 又来，这样…不行
Dude, honestly...
兄弟，说真的…
you've got to be a little more positive about these things, all right?
在这种情况下应该想开点，对吧？
- Yeah? - Positive about what? I don't...
- 不是吗？ - 怎么想开点？我不…
First of all, look at this beautiful Alabama landscape, OK?
第一，要懂得欣赏阿拉巴马的迷人风光，对吧？
You don't get shit like this in New Jersey.
新泽西哪有这样的地方
God, you...
天啊，你…
Hey, look, dude.
嘿，看
It's a baby deer.
一只小鹿
- Wow. Man. - Shit.
- 哇，看 - 真是
Hey. Hey.
嘿，嘿
Look how cute this deer is, dude. Not like those asshole deer in New Jersey.
你瞧这小鹿多乖巧，不像新泽西那群该死的鹿
I know, man.
那是
- Hey, buddy. - Dude, Alabama's awesome.
- 好啊，小东西 - 哥们，阿拉巴马不错吧
He likes you.
他喜欢你
- Oh, my God! - No!
- 哦，我的妈啊！ - 不是吧！
Sorry about that. I was in my zone.
受惊了，这是我的区
What the hell are y'all doing out here in them fancy clothes?
你们穿这么花哨来这干嘛？
We were on our way to Texas and we got lost.
我们想去德州，迷路了
Texas?
德州？
You're a long way from Texas.
还远着呢
No!
不要！
Born in '04.
04年的
Get in here.
进来吧
Yeah. The sun's about to go down.
瞧，太阳快下山了
- Y'all need a place to stay? Ya hungry? - Yeah, sure.
- 要找地方过夜吗？你们饿吗？ - 是啊，的确
You want to follow me?
那跟我来吧？
Come on.
走吧
Maybe we shouldn't.
我看算了吧
It's already dead. You need a hand, dude?
横竖都是死，要帮忙么，伙计？
My grandpappy bought this land in 1902.
我爷爷1902买下这块地
Very nice, sir.
有眼光，先生
This place is gonna suck.
这里好恐怖
Honey, I'm home.
亲爱的，我回来了
I'm in here.
我在这儿
I wish you'd-a told me you was bringing guests home.
来客人也不提前打个招呼
I'da straightened up in here.
我好打扫一下
Fellas, this is my wife Raylene.
朋友们，这是我老婆瑞琳
Raylene, meet Harold and Kumar.
瑞琳，这是哈罗德和库马
Hello.
你好
Can't shake. I've just got... deer head all over me.
就不握手了，鹿的…搞得我到处都是
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you boys.
- 幸会 - 很高兴认识你们
- You just make yourselves at home. - Thank you.
- 二位别客气 - 谢谢
Honey, something's wrong with that dSL.
亲爱的，网络有点问题
Every time I go on the online, it says, "Searching for server."
我一联网就显示“正在连接服务器”
You try unplugging the AirPort base?
你把无线接入断开了没有？
Yeah, I done did that but it didn't work.
断了，还是不管用
What you need to go online fors, anyways?
你这么急着上网干嘛？
I was gonna get one of them new portable satellite radios.
我想选一个新的手提卫星广播
What the fuck you need a satellite radio for?
你他妈要那玩意干嘛用？
Don't you be cussin' when we got company over.
有客人的时候你嘴巴干净点
- Guys. - Please don't worry about us.
- 二位 - 别管我们
We cuss all the time.
我们整天爆粗口
Who do you think you is, hitting me?
你算老几，敢打老子？
Who do you think bought you that Prada bag?
谁给你买的普拉达手袋？
I told you I wanted a Gucci one.
我要的是古琦包好不好
The Gucci bag cost more!
古琦包贵得更离谱！
Well, Jan Sapperstein's husband sure could afford it.
是吗，人家简・萨帕斯坦因的老公就买得起
Here we go again with Jan Sapperstein.
又和她比了
I don't give a rat's ass what that bitch got.
那婊子有什么干老子鸟事
You be happy with what you have.
你还嫌你的少么
What I have is a husband who ain't worth a turd!
我有的就是一个连坨屎都不如的老公！
You wanna give me shit now?
你嫌弃我啦？
- That's right! - After everything I let you buy!
- 没错！ - 白给你买这买那了！
Even look at the credit card bills?
看过信用卡上的余额吗？
...you buy?! Do you think we need another set of golf balls?
你买的？！你连套高尔夫球都没有还好意思？
- Even worse is the credit card miles. - Stinky, smelly, motherf...
- 更恶心的是刷卡赠的里程 - 恶心，发臭，你娘的…
Guys, we're just gonna get out of here.
二位，我们刚好想出去走走
Nonsense. Don't be silly. You're our guests.
乱讲，别傻了，你们是客
You guys have got to stay for supper.
你们今晚必须留下来吃饭
- No, we couldn't. That's... - No, thank you. We really couldn't...
- 不，不用麻烦了… - 不，多谢了，我们真的…
Of course, we're gonna have to get high first.
废话少说，咱们先来爽上一下
We're close.
他们就在附近
This is news to me. I never knew farmers smoked weed.
这倒挺新鲜的，还没听说农场的人也抽大麻
You ever tried farmin' not high? It's borin' as shit.
不然整天务农？烦都烦死了
You know, this is great, guys.
说实在的，真不错
I kind of always, you know, sort of assumed...
我以前总以为…
that people from the South were kinda...
南方的人都是那种…
A bunch of dumb rednecks?
都是大老粗？
- No. - No, no, no, no, no, no, no. That's not...
- 不是 - 没，没，不是…
We do try to keep our inbred son in the basement when we have company.
不过有客人来的时候 我们真的会把亲生儿子关在地下室哦
Guys, I didn't mean it like that. I was just...
伙计，我不是这个意思，我是说…
Look at their faces!
瞧他们那表情！
Fuck, fuck!
糟了！糟了！
Shit, they found us. They found us. They found us.
惨了，他们找上门了，他们来了，来了
- What do you mean, they found you? - Listen, I'm so sorry. I am so sorry.
- 什么叫他们找你们来了？ - 抱歉，实在抱歉
Are you boys in some kind of trouble?
你们俩惹什么麻烦了吗？
All right. This is gonna sound crazy, but, basically...
好吧，我知道有点荒谬，但简单说
we were on a plane to Amsterdam...
我们乘飞机去阿姆斯特丹
and we got mistaken for terrorists and we got sent to Guantanamo Bay...
我们错被当成恐怖分子，送到关塔那摩湾
and then we escaped and snuck into America with a bunch of Cubans...
然后我们逃出来跟着几个偷渡的古巴人回了美国
and now we're trying to get to Texas...
接着要赶去德州…
where there's a guy who can help us out...
在那儿有人能帮我们…
and he's getting married to Kumar's ex-girlfriend.
他就要和库马的前女友结婚了
Yes.
是的
OK. That's cool.
好啊，精彩
- I understand that. - You do?
- 我懂了 - 真的？
Like the government's never screwed us over before. You know what?
谁没被政府收拾过，知道吗？
Y'all come down here and hide in the basement. I will handle this.
你们躲到地下室去，我来顶着
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, both.
谢谢！谢谢！谢谢二位
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢，谢谢
OK. This isn't creepy.
不错嘛，没那么可怕
What the hell is that?
那是什么鬼东西？
You're walking towards the creepy music?
你要开那个可怕的音乐盒？
Ge...
过...
This song rocks, dude.
这曲子挺温馨嘛
Kumar.
库马
Hey, dude, there's a lighter here with a clown on it.
下面有个小丑打火机
Jesus Christ, there's a fucking monster!
妈呀，有怪物！
God!
上帝！
Hey, you don't happen to have a Baby Ruth on you, do you?
嘿，你身上没带糖果吧？
No. Why do you need a Baby Ruth?
没，要糖果干什么？
That's how Chunk won over Sloth in The Goon/es.
七宝奇谋里面小矮子就这么打败怪物斯洛斯的
This thing looks like Sloth?
那东西象斯洛斯吗？
All I saw was the creature's hand.
我只看见一只手
The hand looks like Sloth?
手像不像斯洛斯？
The fucking hand of an evil monster, dude. Like fucking claws and shit.
绝对是只邪恶怪物的手，恶心的爪子
Shit.
妈的
Listen, no matter what, don't let the creature know that it's ugly, OK?
听着，不管怎样都不能让怪物知道它自己很怪 懂吗？
The last thing that we want to do is criticize it or make it feel different...
千万不能让他看出我们觉得他丑陋怪异…
just because it was born with horrible deformities.
仅仅是因为他天生残疾
Don't worry. I got rid of 'em. It was just my neighbors.
别怕，我来处理，是我的邻居
- There's a fricking Cyclops... - No, you got...
- 下面有个独眼人… - 不，你们…
...in your basement, man! ...a fucking thing, dude!
就在地下室，天啊！怪物，伙计！
You met Cyrus.
你们看到赛勒斯了
- Cyrus. - You named it?
- 赛勒斯 - 你还给它取名字了？
Our son.
我们的儿子
You must have woke him up. He was supposed to be asleep. I'm sorry.
你们肯定是把他吵醒了，他这时候该睡着的 抱歉
I thought you were joking...
我还以为你是说笑的…
when you said you had an inbred son who lives in your basement.
你说你们把儿子关在地下室
Well, it ain't a joke.
是啊，不是开玩笑
Raylene and I here are siblings, and we get it on.
瑞琳和我是亲兄妹，我们相爱了
But that don't mean we ought to be judged.
可我们不该因此受罚
You boys must be awful tired after what you've been through.
你们受惊了，得好好休息一下
Come with me, I'll show you to your bed.
跟我来，带你们去卧室
You better go back to sleep, boy!
你给我回去睡觉，小子！
Don't make me come down there and whip your Cyclops ass!
别等老子下去抽你独眼屁股！
It's tough love.
这是粗暴的爱
It's the best way.
最佳方式
I don't know what I was thinking dating that douchebag Colton.
我也不知道自己怎么跟克尔顿这个混球谈上了
He is a douchebag. What were you thinking?
他那个混球，你当时脑子进水了？
But it was agony pretending his puny, little penis satisfied me.
最为难的事还是 得装出他那个短小的家伙对我很受用
I bet. I bet you've been missing the thundercock too, haven't you, baby?
我就知道，你肯定怀念我的火箭炮了吧，宝贝？
- Yeah. - Yeah?
- 是啊 - 真的？
Yeah, you've been missing it?
真的，想要了吧？
How much?
有多想？
- A lot. - I bet.
- 很想 - 了解
Well...
呃…
- I kind of have this fantasy. - What is it?
- 我有过这种幻想 - 什么？
I thought it'd be kinda cool to bring somebody else in bed with us.
我带了一个跟我们一起享受床第之欢
Who?
谁？
Hey, baby.
嘿，宝贝
- Yeah! - Yeah?
- 好啊！ - 好吗？
- Yeah. - She's hot, right?
- 好 - 她挺性感，对吧？
Let's do it.
来吧
Faster, Weedy.
再快点儿，小麻
Teeth, teeth, Weedy, teeth.
牙齿，咬到了，小麻，牙
- Weedy! - Yeah?
- 小麻！ - 爽吗？
- Yeah! - You like that?
- 爽！ - 过瘾吗？
Putting it in the ass now, Weedy.
该菊花了，小麻
Yeah, how about that?
爽啊，刺激吗？
Wow.
哇
Dude.
兄弟
I just had the most fucked-up nightmare.
我刚做了个吓死人的噩梦
Come on, man. I was having a really hot dream.
讨厌，我的淫梦正高潮呢
Go back to bed, please, dude.
接着睡吧，好吧
Why did we have to leave? Their Goon/es child was kind of cute.
干嘛非要走？他们家独眼小孩挺可爱嘛
I don't care. It tried to fucking bite me.
我才懒得看，他要咬我
Jesus, every time the two of us try to get anywhere...
天啊，有咱俩的地方…
it's fucking disaster after fucking disaster.
就有没完没了的倒霉事
Jesus, dude. Here, you really need a hit of this.
别激动，来点儿吧
Dude, I don't want a fucking hit!
算了，我才没兴趣！
It's your solution to everything, you know that?
只有你才靠这个逃避一切责任，知道吗？
Think about it. We should be at Colton's already.
想想吧，咱们本该到克尔顿那儿了
Hey, chill, we still have two days to fuck up the wedding.
急什么，去砸他们的婚礼还有两天时间呢
- What?
- 什么？
That's what this is all about, isn't it? You want to fuck up the wedding.
你就是想着这个，对吧？你要把他们婚礼搞砸
It's not fucking funny, Kumar. It's not fucking funny!
这可不是闹着玩儿，库马 这一点都不好玩
Colton is the only guy that can help us out at this point.
到这个份上，克尔顿是最后的希望了
I can't believe... I cannot believe you're willing to fuck that up!
想不到…想不到你连最后一线希望都要断送
I just hate that fucking asshole, OK?
我讨厌这个混蛋，不行吗？
Yeah? I like him better than I like you right now.
好啊？我现在更讨厌你
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 没错
You know what he got me? A job.
人家给了我什么？一份工作
You know what you got me? Thrown into Guantanamo Bay.
你给了我什么？关塔那摩湾的门票
- Your job sucks. - Admit it.
- 那工作也不怎么样 - 认了吧
You're jealous because Vanessa found somebody better than you.
瓦内萨找到更好的归宿，你就嫉妒
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
你他妈什么意思？
Better than you! Let me think.
比你好！我看看
Potential future president, or unemployed pothead?
有潜质的未来总统跟失业的瘾君子？
Tough. That's tough. That's a tough one for her, isn't it?
难，真难，她可真难抉择，是吧？
Yeah, well at least Vanessa's not in Amsterdam...
就算是，至少瓦内萨没有在阿姆斯特丹…
getting plowed by a bunch of European dudes.
跟一群欧洲佬搞得七荤八素
- What? - Do you really think Maria's...
- 什么？ - 你还真以为玛丽亚会...
saving herself for you, dude?
一直等着你啊，哥们？
Right now, she's probably got two uncircumcised dicks...
此时此刻，说不定她正忙着…
dangling in front of her throat.
用嘴巴伺候两条棒棒呢
You know what she's gonna do with them? Down 'em into her tonsils?
你想得到她是怎么玩儿的吗？深入喉咙？
Fucking dick.
混蛋操的
- That's my hat. - That was my hat, bro.
- 你把我帽子仍了 - 你也把我帽子扔了
Maria, Maria, Maria, Maria.
玛丽亚，玛丽亚，玛丽亚，玛丽亚.
Asshole!
混蛋！
Don't you dare say a fucking word about my angel!
你再说我的天使一个脏字试试看！
What the fuck was that?
那边怎么了？
Get up. Get up!
起来，起来！
Fuck you.
滚蛋
Shit.
妈的
Isn't that a KKK bonfire?
是三K党营火会？
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, I think it is.
我看是
Maybe we should get the fuck out of here.
我看咱们赶紧跑路吧
Yeah. Yeah, dude.
是啊，哥们
Let's do that.
越快越好
The other day, caught a rerun of that show Becker.
那天，看到重拍贝克尔那部电视剧
You know that show?
知道那个剧吧？
Yeah, that's the one with that Jew, Ted danson.
知道，就是泰德・丹森演的那个
That blond negro they got on there, he had me in stitches.
那白妞和黑人搞在一起，笑死我了
He's actually pretty funny.
他可真有意思
Really? You think so?
真的？你觉得好玩儿？
I'm not saying I wouldn't lynch the guy, but...
我一样鄙视他，不过…
his timing, it's priceless.
他的时代，真是无可复制
Hold up a second.
等等
I gotta go drain the main vein.
我得放放水
I'll tell ya, Travis...
告诉你，特拉维斯...
when it comes to feeling good...
爽的时候…
I'd rate pissin' right up there with comin' and shittin'.
我喜欢连屎带尿一起来
I like to do all three.
我还想三种一起来呢
Yeah, I hear ya.
我明白你说的
Kenny, come on, man. Hurry the fuck up.
肯尼，快点，还没完了
You were the one who made me drink that third beer.
你让我喝第三杯的
Hold your horses, peckerwood.
勒马了，啄木鸟
Gross! You fucking pissed on me!
恶心！你尿老子身上了！
- You racist fuck! - What the heck?
- 你个种猪主义者！ - 搞什么？
What the nigger was that?
哪儿来的黑鬼？
This is fucked. We are fucked.
完蛋了，这下完蛋了
Kenny. Travis.
肯尼，特拉维斯
What in the tarnation you guys doin'?
你们俩在这里搞什么？
Good, you brought the keg. Lug that thing over.
太好了，你们把桶带来了，拖过去
- Let's go! Come on! - Come on!
- 走啦！快点！ - 来啊！
Let's go, come on!
走啊，快啊！
Yeah, then you put little onions on 'em and you steam 'em, they're awesome.
对啊，然后你们放几片洋葱上去一蒸，好极了
Roldy, dude, I'd never thought I'd say this in a million years...
罗迪，这话我以前可绝对说不出口…
but the Klan really knows how to party.
不过这些教徒还真会玩儿
You gotta try these dogs.
来片狗肉
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
- 真的？ - 是啊
Really know how to... the Klan knows how to party?
知道人家三K党怎么玩儿了？
- Dude, we've got to get out of here! - Jeez, all right, dude, relax.
- 傻瓜，咱们得赶紧离开这儿！ - 天呀，当然，放松
All right, y'all! Come on over here and we'll sit around the campfire.
好了，各位！我们围坐在篝火边
- Shit, what do we do? - Let's go sit down.
- 糟了，咱们怎么办？ - 坐过去
Rufus. Next to them marshmallows...
鲁弗斯，把果汁软糖…
- and the graham crackers. - Everybody sit down.
- 跟全麦饼干拿过来 - 大伙坐下
Best s'mores we've had in a long time...
好久没有这么好的果盘了…
that's what I'm talking about, that's what I'm talking about.
说的就是，说的就是
Now. Now I want each one of y'all to tell me...
好了，现在你们每个人都要讲一个…
somethin'... Porch monkey, kike!
黑驴的故事，犹太们！
...that you did to a minority this week. Yeah.
说说你们怎么往来的，来吧
I tripped a beaner while I was walking down the stairs...
有天我在沃尔玛下楼的时候
at the Wal-Mart the other day.
拌了一个墨西哥佬一下
Guy crashed into a bunch of wine bottles.
那家伙摔到一堆酒瓶边上
They made him pay for 'em! Yeah!
他们让他赔钱！耶！
All right, all right, let's all calm down.
好了好了，大家静一静
White power here, white power here, white power here.
白权，白权，白权
Giving him what he deserves.
他自作自受
Hebe!
赫伯！
All right, I'm back. Next.
好了，我回来了，下一个
It better be good. Here.
希望更精彩
Come on, dude, say something.
来啊，哥们，随便说说
You know what?
你们知道吗？
I did knee an Indian guy in the balls.
我用膝盖顶过一个印度人的蛋蛋
That's funny!
好玩啊！
Yeah, send them Indians back to Africa.
耶，把印度人踢回非洲
Well, you want to hear something real fucked-up and awesome that I did?
你们想听听我有什么更猛的料吗？
I took a Korean guy's toothbrush and I rubbed it all over my dick.
我用一个韩国人的牙刷清洁我的家伙
- You did that? - Well, that's just downright disgustin'.
- 你真干过？ - 这个可是够让人反胃的
- But I like it! - Yeah!
- 我就喜欢这样的！ - 好！
Yeah, I love bein' white.
好唷，白人好啊
- What the... - Look what we got us here, brothers.
- 你们… - 大伙开开眼界吧
Mexicans!
墨西哥人！
Lynch 'em!
扁死他们！
Come on, come on! Come on!
快跑！快！
Come on, boys, let's chase them back to the border!
大家快啊，把他们赶出边境！
Pussy fart!
狗屁东西！
Holy shit!
我的天啊！
Should we put it out or what?
我们要不要救火？
Are they still behind us?
甩掉了么？
I don't think so. Dude, the Klan is fucking slow.
甩开了，这帮家伙真慢
Hey, flag down this car.
嘿，拦住这车
Help! Help! Help!
救命！救命！救命！
- Thank you.
- 多谢
Thanks for stopping.
多谢搭救
No problem.
小事一桩
Neil?
尼尔？
Gary and Kumar!
加里和库马！
- Yeah.
- 是啊
Harold. Harold.
哈罗德，哈罗德
Sorry, man. I forgot.
抱歉，记错了
What are you doing here, man?
你在这干嘛？
This is where God took me. What are you guys doing out here?
上帝指引我来此，你们呢？
We're actually trying to get to Texas.
我们要去德州
That's where I'm headed!
我也往那边走！
What are the odds?
真巧？
Let's get out of here.
上路了
- All right. - Thank you.
- 好 - 谢谢
Shrooms?
要魔菇么？
- No. Thanks, though. - No, thank you.
- 不用，谢谢了 - 不，谢了
Suit yourself.
随便咯
Gentlemen, start your engines.
先生们，发动你们的引擎
It's gonna be a bumpy fuckin' ride.
我们将踏上颠簸的旅程
We found their phone.
我们找到电话了
Lee and Patel made a phone call to you.
李和巴特尔给你们打过电话
Now tell us everything you know about their terrorist plot.
乖乖地把他们的恐怖计划交待清楚吧
Terrorist plot? Rold and Kumar?
恐怖计划？他们俩？
This is ridiculous.
真搞笑
OK, fine. Fine.
好啊，好
Mr. Rosenberg.
罗森伯格先生
Mr. Gold-stein.
古德斯坦因先生
We'll do it your way.
那就按着你们的玩儿法
What's this? What do we have here?
这是什么？干嘛用的？
It's about seven dollars?
就是七美金？
Look, don't insult us, all right?
听着，少来这套，好吧？
I don't know what the hell is going on here...
我不知道这是什么狗屁…
but I'm pleading the Fifth until I speak to my lawyer.
不过等我的律师来了，我会根据第五修正案上诉
You're pleading the Fifth, huh?
你要上诉第五修正案，啊？
Beecher, give me a copy of the Bill of Rights.
比彻，给我一份权利和自由法案
The Bill of Rights? Why?
权利和自由法案？干嘛？
Just do it!
少废话！
Excuse me.
失陪了
Five, right?
五，对吧？
- Five alive. - Sure.
- 绝对是五 - 当然
OK. OK. Good.
好，不错
You wanna know what I think about the Fifth Amendment?
想听听我对第五修正案的见解么？
There it is.
告诉你
That's what I think of the Fifth Amendment.
这就是我的答案
Why the hell is your ass so dirty? Don't you wipe?
你屁股怎么这么脏？不擦的么？
Don't ask questions you don't want the answer to, buddy.
别自讨没趣，小子
What do ya got?
有进展了么？
Turns out the FBI was already tapping Mr. Goldstein's phone.
FBI早就开始监听古德斯坦因先生的电话了
- We got what we need. - Wait a second.
- 有点内容 - 等等
You were tapping my phone?
你们监听我的电话？
You want to hear the tape?
想听听带子么？
No. I'm sick of listening to this dirt farmer. What's the upshot?
不必，听厌了这个土包，结果如何？
Lee and Patel are on their way to Texas as we speak.
跟我们分析的一样，李和巴特尔往德州去了
I knew they'd trip up.
就知道他们会漏出马脚的
Ready the plane. These fuckers are goin' down.
准备飞机，这些操蛋该收场了
Neil, can you just focus on driving? You've had... Focus on the road.
尼尔，你能专心开车么？你还…专心看路
You've had dozens of shrooms, my friend.
魔菇还有很多，朋友
Dude, I was able to perform an appendectomy at age 14.
哥们，我14岁就会做阑尾炎切除术
I think I can handle a couple mushrooms.
几个小魔菇太不足挂齿了
- Wasn't that just a TV show? - Jesus Christ!
- 那个不是电视上的么？ - 啊呀吗呀！
Did you see that unicorn?
你们看见那个独角兽了吗？
Lts horn was so shiny.
它的角真闪亮
So, why are you guys headed to Texas?
对了，你们去德州有事么？
Let's just say my ex-girlfriend's getting married.
简单说就是我前女友要结婚了
The one that got away, huh?
劈腿的那个，啊？
Yep.
是啊
Sounds to me like you need a drink.
哥们建议你来两杯
Road. Neil, please, can you pay attention...
看路，尼尔，求你了，专心点…
dude, I've got it!
兄弟，我心里有数
- Yeah, but... - He's a good driver. Stop.
- 没错，可… - 他技术过硬，闭嘴
Thanks, man. Cheers, dude.
写了，干杯，兄弟
Really? Drinking?
真喝啊？
I have a lost-love story of my own.
我也有段伤心往事
Yeah?
噢？
Happened on the set of C/ara's Heart.
是在紫色爱心的片场认识的
Sure, sure, yeah.
噢，知道，知道
I'll never forget her. Her name was Tashonda.
我永远记得她，她叫塔琼达
She was Whoopi Goldberg's stand-in.
她是乌比・戈德堡的替身
Her skin was so soft, her lips were so sweet.
她皮肤柔软，朱唇甜蜜
She had these tiny, little Hershey Kiss nipples...
她是那种小小的黑妞乳头…
that you just wanted to suck on all night long.
让你整晚都舍不得松口的那种
Anyway, last day of shooting, I told her.
之后，拍摄的最好一天，我跟她说
I said...
我说…
"T-Bird, we're gonna have to break up."
“雷鸟，我们分手吧”
Why did you do that?
你干嘛这么做？
I didn't think I could take on that kind of responsibility.
我觉得那时候还负不起这个责任
It was such a big mistake.
真是一失足成千古恨
Why? I mean, with T-Bird gone...
为什么？难道，雷鸟走了…
couldn't you have sex with whoever you wanted?
你就不能跟你喜欢的人做爱了吗？
Let me be clear.
我再跟你清楚点儿
There is nothing on the planet...
这个世界上…
that I love more than a hot, new pussy.
我最爱的就是性感火辣的小妞
- Sure. - Nothing.
- 那是 - 绝对
What does the P.H. Stands for in N.P. H?
我名字N.P.H里的P.H.是表示什么？
Patrick Harris.
帕特里克・哈里斯
No, common mistake. Poon handler.
错，惯性思维，训阴者
The point is, boys...
说到底，兄弟…
even though I love havin' sex with some hot, random trim...
即便我再放浪形骸
a day hasn't gone by where I haven't thought of Tashonda.
心中依然挂念塔琼达
Every time I see a bag of Hershey's Kisses, my balls get so wet.
每次看见黑妞接吻，我就湿了
Here's to you, Tashonda.
敬你，塔琼达
- I hope you kept the baby. - Wow.
- 希望你没把孩子做掉 - 天
Hey, honey. What's up?
嘿，亲爱的，怎么了？
I found something in your purse.
在你包里发现了点东西
Why would you go through my purse?
你翻我包干嘛？
Why would you have a joint...
你怎么还有这些烟卷
when you know it could ruin my political career?
明知道这东西可能毁了我的前程
I'm sorry.
抱歉
What with all the wedding plans, I've just been a little stressed.
婚礼太隆重，我有点吃不消
It helps me relax?
这个能解压？
Marijuana is illegal, Vanessa.
大麻是违禁药品，瓦内萨
Now, I thought that part of your life was in the past.
我希望这东西成为你的过去式了
- It is. - Good.
- 我保证 - 很好
That's all I need to hear.
就等你这句话呢
Hey, baby.
嘿，宝贝
Look, I know things can be hectic with the wedding.
好了，我知道婚礼的事儿让人睡不好觉
But, you know, if you get stressed out, just do what I do.
要是真难受，就跟我一样
Snort Zoloft, OK?
吸点郁乐复
What the fuck?
搞什么鬼？
Shit.
完蛋了
Dude, they set up a fucking roadblock! They're gonna find us.
他们设置了路障，专门搜查我们的
- What are you talking about? - Neil...
- 你们说什么呢？ - 尼尔
I don't know how to say this any other way, man, but we're fugitives.
我不知道该怎么说清楚，我们现在是逃犯
Cool.
牛啊
OK, well, we've got to find a way to get out of this.
我们的想办法逃过他们的法眼
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Please.
- 没错，没错，没错 - 摆脱你了
You act like I've never smuggled a fugitive across state lines before.
我又不是第一次带囚犯过境
Here. Hide in that.
拿着，藏好
Sorry. It's a little sticky.
抱歉，有点黏乎乎的
Shit.
妈的
Yeah.
爽
What the... When were you gonna show me these?
你他妈…你打算什么时候给我看？
Excuse me.
打扰
Wait, Officer!
等等，长官！
- Shit. - Hold that car!
- 糟了 - 拦住那辆车！
Neil Patrick Harris.
尼尔・帕特里克・哈里斯
Yo.
唷
It is an honor to meet you, sir.
很荣幸见到您，先生
Yeah. I would imagine so.
看出来了
I'm sure you get this all the time...
我也知道常常有人这么说…
but your part in Starsh/p Troopers truly, truly changed my life.
可您在《星河战队》的角色深深的改变了我的人生
Really?
是吗？
How?
说说看？
Well, no one thought the war against the arachnids of Klendathu could be won.
没人看好你们跟那些蜘蛛怪的那场斗争
- But you showed the starship troopers... - Neil!
- 可你用行动告诉站队的士兵们… - 尼尔！
...that those bugs could be destroyed.
虫子并非坚不可摧
A lot of people think the war on terror is a war that can't be won, right?
好多人认为恐怖势力不可战胜，对吗？
That's why I joined the department of Homeland Security.
为此我加入保卫祖国安全的事业
My friend, two words. Starsh/p fuckin' Troopers.
朋友，两个词，星际战舰，士兵
If you want to know the secret of being, you will come with us.
如果你想了解人类的奥秘，请跟我们来
Please. I really need to go.
抱歉，我赶时间
Yeah, of course. I'm so sorry to bother you. You move along.
当然，抱歉打扰您了，请便
Bye.
再见
I love you.
我爱你
I love you too, Mr. Patrick Harris.
我也爱你，帕特里克・哈里斯先生
What the...
怎么…
Holy fucking shit, that was awesome.
真够扯的，干得漂亮
Try having that conversation on shrooms.
靠魔菇的劲儿跟他讲话的
I deserve an Oscar for that performance.
强烈要求奥斯卡最佳表演奖
- You do! - Dudes...
- 当然！ - 兄弟们…
I'm gonna take a little detour on the way, all right?
路上小住一下，怎么样？
- No. - Neil, no.
- 别 - 尼尔，别
But we're almost there, man.
可我们就快到了
- No buts. No buts! - What do you do...
- 没有可是，没有可是！ - 你这么干…
I'm going to a whorehouse and I'm gonna get my fuck on.
我得找个青楼发泄一下
If you two don't want to get your dicks wet, that's fine with me.
你们也想来点刺激，就跟着我吧
I'll get my dick wet.
我要点刺激
Pussy, I'm home!
小妞，我回来啦！
Hello?
在么？
Well, well, well. I thought you'd never show your face around here again.
唷唷唷，我还以为你一去不复返了
What's the matter, Sally? I thought I was one of your top customers.
你是怎么回事，萨利？
Have you forgotten what happened the last time you were here?
真是贵人多忘事啊？
Because of you, my best girl quit.
因为你，我最好的丫头不干了
Hey, I paid her good money.
嘿，我给了她个好价钱
It's not my fault she didn't lube up.
又不是我的错，她太干涩
Besides, I bring you new customers.
而且，我还带了新客
- New customers? - No, Neil, that's all.
- 新客？ - 不，尼尔，没必要
Thank you. Thank you. Appreciate it. Appreciate it.
多谢，多谢，我们心领了
Sally. Bring on the lineup.
萨利，让她们上阵吧
Line up in the chutes, girls.
排开队列，姑娘们
Longhorns coming through.
欢迎长角牛
Neil.
尼尔
Bigger. Bigger. Bigger. Bigger.
够大，更大，还大，再大
Hello, ba...
嗨，宝…
- What's your name, miss? - Tits Hemingway.
- 小姐，请问尊姓大名？ - 乳乳・海明威
How'd you come up with that?
何得此名？
Well, I have huge tits.
哦，我宝贝比较大
And my favorite book is A Moveab/e Feast.
最喜欢的小说是《流动的盛宴》
I guess that makes sense, yeah.
言之有理
Well, I hope you're ready for me, Tits...
好吧，希望你也准备好跟我大战了，乳乳…
'cause I'm gonna rock out with my cock out...
我会用我的钢炮干得你无路可逃
and you're gonna jam out with your clam out.
你也会乐此不疲
It's gonna be magical.
魔力四射
- The whores are on me, fellas. - No, Neil...
- 这妞我要了，伙计们 - 不，尼尔…
- thank you, but we... that's... - Thanks, dude.
- 谢谢你的好意，可我们得… - 谢了老兄
Screw that, Roldy. I don't know about you...
别扫兴了，罗迪，真是不明白
but, no offense to the rest of you ladies, I am gonna be taking you two.
其他的姑娘也很棒，不过我只能用两位了
No, Kumar. Kumar!
回来，库马，库马！
Roldy, you're missing out, brother.
罗迪，顾不得你了，兄弟
Yo, we need to get back on the road, buddy.
嘿，快过来咱们得赶路了
We need...
不然…
Well, now, you know, we also supply...
那么，其实，我们也提供…
in-room films or a magazine.
室内电影或杂志
Well, if you'd like some self-satisfaction...
要是您习惯自助…
we do have some...
我们也提供…
electronic devices right over there.
便利的电子设备
Just have some coffee. Yeah?
咖啡就好，可以么？
Why don't you lie on the bed?
快躺下吧？
And tell us what you want us to do.
有要求就大胆讲吧
OK. OK.
好啊好啊
Well...
那
how about...
要不
How about you take off your clothes and make out with each other?
要不你们就脱掉衣服跟对方亲热？
- We've done that before. - We can do that.
- 老把戏了 - 没问题
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 当然
Can you use tongue?
能舌吻么？
Bump your titty on her titty.
咪咪挤咪咪
Boner achieved!
够过瘾！
Great. Now let's get those pants off.
行了，把裤子脱了吧
OK.
好吧
- You are benevolent human beings. - Yeah, I know.
- 你们真是好人 - 我们也这么认为
- Yeah? - We get that a lot.
- 真的？ - 我们很清楚这点
Yeah. You know what that means, benevolent?
是么，你们知道好的意思么？
Yeah, I do, actually.
当然了
What?
什么意思？
It means we're gonna fuck you so hard...
意思是我们猛劲干你…
your dick's gonna be sore for two weeks.
叫你老二酸上两周
That is exactly, exactly what it means.
真是最最精准的解释
You know what bothers me the most, though?
你们知道我最窝火的是哪一点吗？
He never once apologized for getting me into all this trouble.
就是他从没为此表过一次歉意
I mean, I'm supposed to be with my Maria right now in Amsterdam, OK?
不是他，我这会儿该跟玛丽亚在阿姆斯特丹甜蜜呢
But it's cool. He doesn't know how to say "I'm sorry."
无所谓，他不会说“对不起”这三个字
Why do you think that is?
你觉得为什么会这样呢？
Sparkle, because it's all about what he wants. It's about him, him, him.
斯巴可，因为他就这样，只顾他自己，自己，自己
You know. I don't even care because... You know...
不过，我都习惯了，懒得理他
if he can't be a good friend to me, I'm not gonna be a good friend to him.
他不把我当兄弟，我也不会把他当朋友
- It's done. - Don't say that.
- 扯平了 - 话不能这样讲
A good friend is hard to come by.
好友缘分难得
Venus, come on.
维纳斯，拜托
Yeah, but if he was a real friend, he would know how to say, "I'm sorry."
是啊，要是他真心对你，他会跟你道歉的
That's right.
没错
Thank you, Agnes.
多谢，艾格尼丝
Nail on the head.
一针见血
It's like right now...
现在的情况是…
after all the shit that we have been through in the last few days...
我跟他这几天经历了这么多磨难…
you know, he's in there having the time of his life, having sex.
他却在那边享受床第之欢
I never should have left her.
我不该丢下她的
I don't even know...
我都不知道…
I don't even know what I was thinking.
自己当时是怎么想的
I loved her so much.
我那么爱她
She was my little baby.
她是我的小宝贝
Why did I let my little baby go?
我怎么放手了呢？
Why did I let her go?
我为什么要和她分开？
You'll find someone else.
你会找到爱情的
No, I won't. Not like Vanessa.
不会了，不像瓦内萨
You'll find love again someday.
天涯何处无芳草
Yeah, you will.
是啊，别急
Did you guys?
你们是指？
No, we're whores.
不，我们是妓女
- Remember? - Yeah.
- 忘了？ - 对啊
Oh, my God. Are you OK?
老天啊，没事吧？
What the hell is going on here?
这是怎么回事？
That prick fucking branded me!
帕特里克把老娘屁股给烙了！
- Stop it. - I warned you, Neil.
- 少来 - 我警告你，尼尔
Bring it.
来啊
- Neil! Neil! - Time to put your dick in the dirt.
- 尼尔！尼尔！ - 你那家伙长得不耐烦了
- What... Neil! What are you doing? - Come on. Come on. Come on.
- 怎么…尼尔！你干嘛？ - 快走，快走，快走
- But... - No, Neil.
- 可… - 不，尼尔
Neil!
尼尔！
- What about Neil, man? - No, fuck Neil. He just fucked us.
- 就不管尼尔了？ - 管他干嘛，他都不管我们
- Neil! Neil! - Come on, come on, come on!
- 尼尔！尼尔！ - 快点！过来过来
- Come on! Come on! Come on! - Neil!
- 上车！上车！上车！ - 尼尔！
Come on!
快点！
- N.P. H! - No!
- 尼帕哈！ - 不！
Stop! Stop!
停车！停车！
Wait, wait, wait, wait! We've got to get Neil.
等等等等！得把尼尔带上
- Why? - Look, we're stealing his car!
- 怎么？ - 不然咱们就成偷车贼了
- We can't leave him back there. - He stole your fucking car last week!
- 不能丢下他不管 - 他上周才偷了你的车！
What was that?
那是什么？
- Hurry up. - Neil!
- 快点！ - 尼尔！
- Hurry up. Come on, man. - Guys.
- 快，加油！ - 兄弟
- All right. Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up. - Neil, Neil, come on! Come on, man!
- 好了，快快快！ - 尼尔，尼尔，快过来，快点！
- Guys! - Hurry up! Hurry up!
- 兄弟们！ - 上车！上车！
It's not even funny. Hurry up, dude, hurry up.
她们来真的，快啊，哥们，快
You can make it, dude.
你行的
Oh, my God! Holy shit!
噢，天啊！要命！
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God! - Jesus Christ!
- 噢，妈呀，妈呀！ - 老天爷！
- Neil's dead! Neil's dead! - No!
- 尼尔死了！他死了！ - 不！
- Oh, my God! - Get the fuck out of here! Go! Go!
- 老天爷 - 快走！快快快！
It's the dawn of a new day.
又是新一天拂晓
And Neil Patrick Harris isn't around to see it, man.
可尼尔・帕特里克・哈里斯却再也看不到了
Dude, I told you.
兄弟，都说了多少次了
Will you please stop saying that?
别念叨了行吗？
God.
天
He's gone.
他死了
Maybe he's got some family contact info in here.
或许这里有他家人的联系方式
Dude, I know I'm not calling Neil's parents.
哥们，要通知家属就你来
What's in the bag?
包里有什么？
- Holy fuck. - Creepy mask.
- 吓死老子了 - 恐怖面具
A jar with hair in it.
装头发的罐子
And, like, 12 cans of Mace.
好像，还有12瓶催泪瓦斯
- Look, dude. - Holy shit.
- 好了，哥们 - 天啊
Holy shit, we actually made it.
天啊，终于到了
This is where Colton grew up, huh?
克尔顿就在这种地方长大的吗？
Smell that? That smells like douche.
闻到了么？闻起来就白痴
No, you will remain in this car.
不，你呆在车上
I will go inside alone and, if we're lucky, Colton will help us out.
我自己去就好了，克尔顿给面子的话会帮忙的
- Why can't I just... - No. Let me put it another way.
- 我连… - 不行，这样好了
You leave this car, and our friendship is over.
你下车，咱们就不是兄弟了
- But, Roldy, I just... - Kumar.
-可罗迪，我就… - 库马
Open the door and I will cut your fucking balls off.
敢开车门，我就割了你的蛋蛋
Jesus. OK.
天啊，成
- Balls. - Go.
- 蛋蛋 - 去吧
Hi, I'm a friend of Colton's.
嗨，我是克尔顿的一个朋友
Thank you.
谢谢
God damn it.
妈的
Vanessa? You OK?
瓦内萨？没摔伤吧？
- Kumar? What are you doing here? - Yeah, let me help you up.
- 库马？你怎么来了？ - 是啊，我扶你起来
I thought you were going to Amsterdam.
我还以为你们去了阿姆斯特丹
Yeah, me too. It didn't work out.
是啊，我倒想，没去成
You all right?
没伤着吧？
- Now, does this hurt when I touch it? - Yeah.
- 我这样碰疼不疼？ - 疼
- It does?
- 真疼？ - 是啊
This is just what I need. A limp during the wedding.
我正盼着婚礼之前摔瘸了呢
Can you move it around in a circle?
能转一圈么？
OK, that's what I figured. It's just your ATFL. I don't think you tore it, though.
好了，我猜没什么事，前距腓韧带没受损
So a little ice and massage should do the trick. You'll be fine.
简单敷冰配合按摩就够了，没大问题
Are you gonna tell me why you're here?
还没说你来干嘛呢？
Roldy and I ran into some trouble...
我和罗迪碰上点儿麻烦
and we figured that maybe your Colton could help us out.
我们想着你家克尔顿或许能帮上忙
- Still getting into trouble, huh? - A little bit.
- 还是霉运缠身，啊？ - 有点吧
You remember that time that you broke into the animal lab...
还记着那次你闯进动物试验室
and, like, stole that monkey and put it in Andy Rosenberg's dorm room?
好像偷了只猴子，放到安迪・罗森伯格的寝室去了
OK, first of all, that was Goldstein's idea...
那件事，第一，是古德斯坦因的主义
and second of all...
第二
had I known that the monkey had AldS, I never would have done that.
要是我知道那猴子有艾滋，是不会碰它一指头的
What about you?
你也好不到哪去
You put those disgusting used tampons in Professor Konop's purse.
你把用过的卫生面条塞到康纳普教授的钱包里
- Remember that? - Come on.
- 你忘了？ - 得了吧
She was a bitch and you know it.
她那个贱人你又不是不知道
What's going on here?
这是聊什么呢？
Hey, she actually fell and broke her heel here.
噢，她刚才摔倒了，把鞋跟折断了
Yeah, I twisted my ankle. Kumar was just looking at it.
是啊，我扭伤了脚踝，库马帮我看看
- Why aren't you in the car, Kumar? - Dude, I heard her yell.
- 上车去吧，库马? - 我听到她喊人我才出去的
I thought I told you to stay in the car, man.
交待过你不准下车的
It's OK, man.
无所谓，哥们
No worries.
没什么
Listen, Roldy filled me in on the situation.
听着，罗迪把情况和我说了
But don't worry. I'll make sure my dad takes care of everything.
别担心，我爸会搞定的
Thanks, man.
多谢
In the meantime, you are going to the doctor.
现在，你们先去看下医生
Ramon!
雷蒙！
Ramon. Please bring Vanessa to dr. Harris immediately.
雷蒙！马上带瓦内萨去找哈里斯医生
Bye, Vanessa. Hope you feel better.
再会，瓦内萨，早日康复
- Bye.
- 再见！ - 再见
Guys.
好了
All right.
没事了
All right, guys. Jet's all fueled. You should be home in no time.
燃料都装好了，兄弟们，很快就能到家了
Sweet.
太棒了
Hey, Colton, I can't believe you're doing this for us...
嘿，克尔顿，多谢你不计前嫌…
on the night before your wedding day.
婚礼前还替我们解围
- I really appreciate it. Thank you. - Please don't mention it.
- 真的很感激，谢谢你 - 不足挂齿
Just want to make sure everything works out smoothly.
但愿一切顺利
Are all these planes yours?
这些飞机都是你的么？
No. OK.
不，好了
Rold, come on, of course they are.
Rold，骗你的，当然都是了
This guy's funny. You're funny.
这家伙真逗，你可真逗
- Yeah? - Hey, Colton, man.
- 是吗？ - 嘿，克尔顿，兄弟
Listen, I was wrong about you, dude. You're not a douchebag.
我以前错过你了，你不是个混球
Dude.
兄弟
You know what I mean. I mean, you're a good dude.
你明白我的意思，你是个好兄弟
And I'm happy for you and Vanessa.
我替你和瓦内萨高兴
That's big of you, Kumar.
你能这么想真难得，库马.
- I really appreciate it. - Sure.
- 我也很感激 - 没错
I just can't wait to get back, man.
我都迫不及待要回家了
You're going back all right.
你们会回去的
This time you're not escaping.
这下看你往哪儿跑
Now!
出来！
Go! Move, move, move!
上！快快快！
You are a douchebag...
你还是个混球…
- No. ...you fucking douchebag, fuck you!
- 不 你个混球，干你！
Yeah. The last thing I was letting you guys do is ruin my wedding.
是啊，不然留着你们搅和我的婚礼么
- You did this? - Of course he did this.
- 是你干的？ - 还能有谁
I thought we were friends, man. How could you betray me like this?
我把你当朋友，你怎么能出卖我呢？
Come on, Rold. You and me?
得了吧，Rold，你跟我？
You let me cheat off you in Advanced Accounting.
高级财会我抄了你的
Other than that, I could give a shit about you.
此外咱们屁交情都谈不上
Take 'em away, guys.
把他们带走
When we get out of this I'm gonna fucking kick your fucking ass, man!
等老子出来再好好教训你！
Boy, you're scaring me.
天啊，我好怕怕啊
Well, come on, you're not one of those kung-fu Asians...
省省吧，你以为自己是功夫巨星…
you're a fucking pussy banker, for Christ's sakes.
你个龌龊的银行小职员
- Fuck you! Fuck you! - I'm gonna rip you up, bitch!
- 干你！干你！ - 我会把你碎尸万段的，贱男！
- You'd best watch your back, bitch! - Fuck you, dude!
- 你最好小心点儿，贱男！ - 干死你！
- Fuck you!
- 干你！
I'm awesome.
爽死啦
Looks like you boys picked the wrong side, huh?
这下你们没话说了吧？
Where's your Koran now?
你们的古兰经呢？
We're not even Muslim, you moron...
我们又不是穆斯林，你个猪头
and even if we were, that doesn't make us terrorists.
就算是，也不能就说我们是恐怖分子吧
Hey! I'm talking to you. Get back here!
嘿！跟你讲话呢，回来！
Man. I can't believe we're going back.
天啊，真不敢想我们又回去了
Now do you see why I hate Colton Graham?
这回你明白我为什么憎恨克尔顿 Graham了吧？
Now do you see why I hate you?
这回你明白我为什么恨你了吧？
I asked you specifically to stay in the car.
我特别嘱咐你别离开车
I told you our friendship was at stake.
我警告过你咱们的友谊危如累卵
Vanessa fell down. And I was helping her.
瓦内萨摔着了，我过去帮她
- I don't want to hear the excuses! - It's not an excuse!
- 我不想听借口！ - 不是借口！
I don't want to hear the excuses!
我没兴趣听！
- I heard her yelling! - I don't want to hear it.
- 我听见她在喊人！ - 我不想听
I'm sorry.
对不起
'Kay?
行了吧？
Look at this. Look at this.
看这一切
I fucked up, OK?
我搞的，好了吧？
I fucked up and I always fuck up. I am a fuck-up.
我搞砸了一切，我是个倒霉蛋
You think?
你说呢？
Harold...
哈罗德...
you're my best friend, dude.
你是我最好的哥们儿
You mean the world to me, man. I love you.
你对我来说就是全部，我爱你
Queers.
同性恋
And I promise you, if we figure out...
我向你保证，如果咱们能…
a way to get out of this, I'm gonna change, OK?
能出去的话，我都改，好吗？
It's not just gonna be about Kumar all the time.
库马不是从前那个只关心他自己的人了
It'll be about Kumar and Harold.
将是库马和哈罗德
Harold and Kumar.
哈罗德和库马.
I kind of like the first way better.
我觉得前一种说法更顺口
OK, OK. Harold and Kumar.
行，行，哈罗德和库马
Harold and Kumar.
哈罗德和库马.
It's not all your fault.
也不全怪你
Yeah, it is. I brought weed on the plane.
是我的错，我把大麻带到飞机上
- You got weed? - No. The other plane.
- 你带了大麻？ - 没，另一个飞机
No, I wish Neil Patrick Harris were still alive, that guy fucking loves him.
不，真希望尼尔・帕特立克・哈里斯没死 这家伙喜欢他
He totally would have been able to bail us out.
他肯定能保释咱俩
You just gave me an idea, man.
你倒提醒了我
- What? - I got this.
- 什么？ - 我来
Hey, Burl...
嘿，布尔
- I actually still have some weed. - You do?
- 其实我还有点儿大麻 - 真的？
- Seriously? - Yeah. It's in my pants.
- 没说笑吧？ - 没有，但藏在裤袋里
- Hold up. - You want to smoke now?
- 等等 - 想来点儿么？
Just let me...
让我拿…
- Harold, this is definitely not... ...get it.
- 哈罗德，这可不是…抽烟的
...the time to smoke.
绝佳时间
dude, you took Neil's Mace?
你拿了尼尔的催泪瓦斯？
Been through a lot of shit, figured we might need it.
一贯走霉运，有备无患
Well, good call.
干的好
Derek, can I get another water?
得里克，再给我拿瓶水行吗？
What the fuck?
他妈的怎么回事？
- Keep your hands up. - Please don't shoot us.
- 把手举起来 - 别开枪
- Jesus Christ. OK, OK. - Please don't shoot.
- 上帝啊，好的好的 - 千万别开枪
It will be a cold day in hell before I let you hijack this plane.
你们要敢劫飞机，我就先送你们下地狱
Beecher, what are you doing?
比彻，你疯了吗？
Whose side are you on? I thought I told you to stay in the cockpit!
谁让你过来的，我叫你呆在驾驶舱！
Enough, Fox! I've had enough of your crap!
够了，福克斯 我早受够了你的屁话！
You think that just because I'm smart...
你看穿了我的大智若愚
you can treat me like some dork in gym class?
就真把我当傻子耍吗？
It's obvious these kids are innocent. But you're too dumb to realize that.
傻子都看得出来他们是无辜的，你还固执愚见
You know, it's people like you...
知道吗，就是你这种败类…
who make the world think that Americans are stupid!
玷污了美国人的智商！
Well, we're not stupid! And we're not gonna take this shit anymore!
可我们不能跟着你犯傻！我们受够了！
It's OK, guys.
没事了，孩子们
It's all over now.
都过去了
Everything's gonna be all right.
一切都会好起来的
Jesus!
天啊！
Fuck!
靠！
I don't wanna die!
我不想死！
Kumar!
库马！
- What? - I have the parachute!
- 干嘛？ - 我有降落伞！
Come over here.
过来
How the fuck am I supposed to do that?
我他妈也想过去可怎么过去啊？
Swim!
游过来！
Holy shit.
我的神啊
It's fucking working!
真他妈有效呢！
Yeah!
耶！
I love you, dude.
我爱你，兄弟
Shit!
该死！
Don't worry about him. I have an idea.
别怕他，我有办法
- What? - Hang on.
- 怎么办？ - 抓紧
Fuck you!
你们去死吧！
Man, that was so fuckin' extreme.
天啊，真他妈挑战极限
It was.
确实
- Kumar? - Yeah.
- 库马？ - 啊
Our dicks are touching, aren't they?
我们的老二互相碰头了，是吧？
Yeah, I guess they are.
好像是
- Yeah. - OK, I was just checking.
- 是啊 - 没事，我就是确认一下
Roldy, can you move us out of the way? There's a house coming up down here.
罗迪，你能挪几步吗？下面有栋房子
I have no idea what I'm doing.
一直是伞在控制我
Dude!
完了！
The glass hurt my dick.
老二被玻璃伤了，老二被玻璃伤了
I think I'm OK. Yeah.
人还在，太好了
- Dude. Dude. - Oh, my God.
- 兄弟，兄弟 - 太好了
- No, shit, dude. You all right? - Fuck! I think so!
- 我说，哥们儿你没事吧？ - 天！应该没事
We gotta get out of here before the people who live here find us.
咱们得在主人发现之前赶快撤
I know. They're gonna be...
同意，他们会…
dude? Dude?
哥们儿，哥们儿？
What's up?
怎么了？
- No. - Holy shit!
- 不会吧 - 太绝了！
What the hell are y'all doing in my office?
你们在我这搞什么？
You'd better start giving me some answers!
最好立即回答我！
George? We're gonna be late for that wedding.
乔治？就快赶不上婚礼了
Shit. It's Cheney. Come on, you guys. Keep quiet. Follow me.
妈的，是切尼，你们俩别出声，跟我来
That guy scares the crap out of me. Let's go hide in the guesthouse.
这家伙真是要命，咱们躲到会客室去
- Come the fuck on. - I'm coming.
- 别他妈磨蹭了 - 来了
- This is a cool room. - Yeah.
- 这房间不错 - 当然
Yeah, this is where I come to escape from work.
工作之余我就来这消遣
- Here? - Yes, sir.
- 这？ - 没错
- So who the heck are you guys? - All right.
- 你们是什么人？ - 好的
My name is Harold Lee, sir...
我叫哈罗德・李，阁下
and this is Kumar Patel.
这位是库玛・巴特尔
Anyway, we were on a parachute and we sort of landed on your ranch.
简言之，我们背着降落伞落到您的农场了
Dude, this is weed.
看，这是大麻
That's Alabama Kush.
这是阿拉巴马卡什
That's only the finest.
最优的品种
So you get high and then you put other people who smoke weed in jail?
你爽够了就把其他抽大麻的人关起来？
- That's so hypocritical. - Dude, look...
- 真是伪君子 - 哥们…
Yeah? Well, let me ask you something, Kumar.
是吗？我来问你，库马
- You like giving hand jobs? - No, sir.
- 你喜欢给别人打手枪吗？ - 当然不
- You like getting hand jobs? - Yeah.
- 你们喜欢打手枪吗 - 喜欢
All right. Well, that makes you a fucking hypocriticizer too.
行了，这么说你也够他妈虚伪了吧
So shut the fuck up and smoke my weed.
所以少他妈废话，抽我的大麻
Hey, love.
嗨，爱人
What are you doing here? It's bad luck. The ceremony starts in a hour.
你来干嘛，会不吉利的，还有一个小时就开始了
I just want to let you know...
我来跟你商量一下…
I had catering get an extra case of Coors Light...
我让负责餐饮的人加了一箱银子弹啤酒
in case the President comes.
以备总统莅临
It's his favorite beer.
是他挚爱的啤酒
- Do you think that'll be enough? - I don't know. Yes?
- 你觉得一箱够了么？ - 不知道，够了？
Who cares?
重要吗？
Look, were you able to work everything out with Kumar and Harold?
你会帮库马和哈罗德摆脱困境么？
Don't worry, Chestnut. I took complete care of 'em.
别担心，美女，我会安排妥当的
They thought you guys were terrorizers.
他们把你们当成恐怖分子？
Wait. That's not funny, man. They sent us to Guantanamo Bay.
别笑，一点都不好笑，他们把我送到关塔那摩湾
Fuck! G. Bay?
靠！关湾？
Tell me you didn't eat that cockmeat sandwich.
别说你们尝过那里的鸡蛋饼了
No. No, we did not eat the cockmeat sandwich. We escaped, thank God.
没没没，刚要吃就逃出来了，感谢上帝
That cockmeat sandwich. That's my favorite.
我喜欢那个鸡蛋饼了
Oh, my God.
天啊
- This is good shit. - I know. I know.
- 这东西真不赖 - 那是当然
- I laced it with blow. - Fuck.
- 一般我会配合着吹箫 - 靠
So it knocks you out, and it keeps you going at the same time.
高潮迭起便一发不可收拾
If you like weed so much, why don't you just legalize it?
你这么喜欢，干嘛不把它合法化
Are you fucking kidding me?
你搞笑么？
You know how pissed off my dad would get if I did that?
我这么干的话我老爹得抓狂成什么样？
Holy shit, dude.
天啊，兄弟
My dad's all up in my shit too, about this whole...
我老爹也总掺和我自己的事
- med school thing, right? - I know.
- 不过都是去学医的事，对吧？ - 了解
And it's not that I don't want to be a doctor, but like...
也不是说我不想当医生，可是…
fucking... sometimes I wonder if he's just encouraging me...
有时候会想，他这么鼓励我
because he knows it'll make me happy...
是为了我的幸福呢
or because he wants me to carry on his legacy, you know?
还是为了让我继承他的基业，明白？
You just blew my fuckin' mind.
我倒是感同身受
- Hi. - Hi. You look good.
- 嗨 - 嗨，您真漂亮
Daddy.
老爸
Yeah, it's W.
是，是我
I don't need your friends to tell me what to do anymore.
我不需要你那些朋友指指点点
- No, I'm not being disrespectful. - That's what I say.
- 我不是不敬重 - 我说什么来着
I'm just saying that I can handle my own shit, all right?
我是说，我自己的屁股自己擦，好吧？
I mean, I don't need them to tell me how to do what I have to do.
我不用他们指手画脚
Yeah, dude!
好样的！
Yeah, well you know what? Yeah, well, fuck you, dad.
好啊，你猜怎么？是啊，去你的，老爸
Fuck you!
滚！
- Dude, that was awesome. - You guys are awesome.
- 你可真帅 - 你们才帅
- No. No. - You're awesome!
- 不不 - 你才帅！
- You are awesomer. - Sir, you are awesome.
- 你更帅 - 阁下，您比较帅
Seriously.
真的
Listen, about our situation...
对了，我们的情况…
Fuck that. Listen, guys, guys, guys. I am the fucking President, all right?
得了，兄弟，我是总统，好吧？
That means I get to pardon whoever I want. You guys are in the fuckin' clear.
我想赦免谁都没问题，你俩他妈无罪了
Don't worry.
别操心了
- Holy shit. Are you serious? Thank you. - Oh, my God. Thank you, Mr. President.
- 天啊，你说真的？谢谢 - 上帝啊，多谢总统先生
Yeah.
好了
- Thank you. Thank you. - Don't mention it.
- 多谢，多谢 - 小意思
But, listen, to be honest, after all the shit that we've been through...
不过，经历了这么多…
I don't know if we can trust our government anymore.
我都不知道是否该继续信任政府了
- Trust the government? - Yeah.
- 信任政府？ - 是啊
Heck. I'm in the government and I don't even trust it.
算了，我身在政府都不信它
You don't have to believe in your government to be a good American.
做个好公民不要把政府当做信仰
You just have to believe in your country.
你们要把国家当做信仰
Exactly.
没错
- Exactly. - Right.
- 没错 - 说得好
This is good shit, isn't it?
真是好东西，对吧？
Yeah, it is.
的确
If you guys need anything else, just let me know, all right?
有什么事就尽管开口，知道么？
Actually, Mr. President, there is one thing.
其实还真有件事
- This really came out great. - Yeah, it did, man.
- 真是美轮美奂 - 的确，伙计
I lit a lot of these candles.
我点了很多这种蜡烛
Great.
太好了
- All clear. - Safe to proceed.
- 解除警报 - 安全进入
He's here! I knew he'd come.
他来了！我知道他回来的
All right, let 'em in.
好，让他们进来
- What is happen... - Who is that?
- 怎么回事… - 谁来了？
- Harold? - Kumar?
- 哈罗德？ - 库马？
Ladies and gentlemen, I apologize for interrupting this beautiful ceremony.
女士们先生们，很抱歉打断这绝美的仪式
But there is no way in hell...
但我绝不能容忍…
that I'm letting the only woman I've ever loved marry that piece of shit.
我唯一心爱的女人嫁给这个狗屎
Security, get them out of here, please.
保安，把他们赶出去
These guys? No, see, they're with us. Yeah.
你叫他们？算了，他们是我们一起的
Looks like I got a little more pull with the President than you, bitch.
好像总统跟我更亲哦，贱人
- What the hell is going on? - I'll tell you what's going on.
- 到底是怎么回事？ - 我来告诉你吧
Your fiance promised to get us out of trouble.
你的未婚夫答应帮我们忙
But instead he arranged for us to be sent back to Guantanamo Bay...
却暗地派人把我们送回关塔那摩湾
where we'd be forced to suck Big Bob's fat dick.
让我们品尝大勃的大家伙
- Is this true? - Yeah, it's true.
- 是真的么？ - 千真万确
I'll take care of this myself.
我来亲手处理
- OK, wait. - No...
- 等等 - 不行
You son of a bitch.
你个婊子养的
I loved you, man.
好喜欢你啊
- I can't believe this. - Vanessa, let me explain...
- 难以置信 - 瓦内萨，让我解释…
Explain?
解释？
Explain why you're putting me through...
解释你为什么要我面对…
the most embarrassing moment of my life?
人生中最难堪的一幕吗？
Well, what if I did something embarrassing to myself?
那，我也让自己难堪一下？
Would that make you feel better?
你觉得舒服一些么？
There's nothing you can do that would be this embarrassing.
你还嫌这不够难堪？
I fear that I will always be A lonely number like root three
我怕成为孤独如三的平方根这样的数字
A three is all that's good and right
三表吉祥和如意
Why must my three keep out of sight Beneath a vicious square-root sign?
而为什么我却躲在狠毒的根号下悲戚？
I wish instead I were a nine
也曾妄想幻化为九
For nine could thwart this evil trick With just some quick arithmetic
因为九能轻算而整除恶灵
I know I'll never see the sun
我自知终难拨云见日
As 1.7321
就因为我是1.7321
You fucking tool.
这是玩儿的哪出？
Quiet, anus.
收紧你的屁眼
Such is my reality A sad irrationality
这就是我的命，无辜的哀鸣
When, hark, just what is this I see?
就在此时，听，这是我所见？
Another square root of a three
另外一个三的平方根
Has quietly come waltzing by
正悄然翩翩而至
Together now we multiply
我们叠交在一起
To form a number we prefer
升华为梦想的真数
Rejoicing as an integer
如整数般雀跃
We break free from our mortal bonds
从此破除桎梏
And with a wave of magic wands
魔棒在飞舞
Our square-root signs become unglued
我们挣脱根号
And love for me has been renewed
爱情焕然新生
You were right.
你说的没错
- That was pretty lame. - Told you.
- 这首诗是够逊的 - 没骗你吧
Look, I can't promise you the kind of lifestyle that Colton could.
听着，我不能许诺给你克尔顿这样的生活
And I can't promise you that I'm gonna mature overnight.
我不能保证我一夜间成熟
But what I can promise you is that...
可我发誓能给你…
Sorry, I smoked weed with the President.
抱歉，我跟总统抽得太多
I totally forgot what I was going to say.
全然忘了我的话
I can promise you that I will always love you.
我发誓能永远爱着你
And I'll never try and make you into something that you're not.
永远不会让你为难自己
So, what do you say you take a brother back?
那么，你能答应我了么？
Only if you promise to get me out of this awkward situation...
除非你答应带我逃出这个鬼地方…
as soon as possible.
越快越好
Come here.
来吧
Yeah!
耶！
That's my boy!
好样的！
Ku!
酷！
Come on. Let's get the hell back to Jersey.
走吧，咱们赶紧回新泽西吧
All right, hold on. First we gotta do something for my buddy here.
等等，得先帮兄弟一个忙
- Got to go somewhere. - Where?
- 去一个地方 - 去哪儿？
- Hey.
- 嗨
- No luck, huh? - No.
- 还没消息？ - 没
Called every hotel in the city. I walked all around.
几乎每个酒店都问遍了
I just can't find her anywhere.
就是没找见
- We'll find her. - We'll find her, dude.
- 会找到她的 - 会找到的，兄弟
What?
怎么了？
Oh, my God, there she is.
踏破铁鞋无觅处啊
- Roldy, she's hot. - Dude, go get her!
- 罗迪，她够辣啊 - 哥们，还等什么！
Jesus, I'm sorry, man.
天啊，真遗憾
- So fuck it. Forget about that. - Yeah.
- 算了，别想了 - 是啊
It's probably just some Amsterdam fling, all right?
就当来阿姆斯特丹兜兜风，挺好嘛？
We'll go back to the Jerz...
等咱们回新…
- in a couple of days, all right? - No.
- 过不了几天，就？ - 不行
No, fuck it.
不行，凭什么
I came way too far.
咱们大老远过来了
We went through too much shit to...
还遭了这么多罪
I'm gonna talk to her.
至少要跟她表白
No, no, no, dude, don't go in there.
不不不，哥们，别进去
- Come on. - Just wait.
- 算了 - 别急
Come on, man. Wait till we get back to Jersey.
算了，等回去再说嘛
What the fuck are you doing?
你干嘛呢？
- C'est quo/ ton puta/n de prob/eme, to/? - Harold!
哈罗德！
I didn't understand what you said.
我听不懂你胡扯些什么
- What the fuck are you doing? - What the fuck are you doing, man?
- 你他妈搞什么？ - 你搞什么？
- You're ruining my shot. - You what?
- 我正拍照呢 - 干嘛呢？
Get off my set!
别挡镜头！
I'm so confused. What's...
这是怎么回事，不懂…
- What's going on? - Harold, I'm doing a photo shoot.
- 怎么了？ - 哈罗德，我在拍照
For H/gh T/mes magazine.
给《欢乐时光》拍插图呢
Of course, you're a model. You're very hot. You're a model.
对啊，你是模特，你那么美，原来个模特
Right. I always wondered what you did for a living.
怪不得，我还在想你是干什么的呢
I'm sorry. So, wait a second. So you're not with this dude?
不好意思，这么说你们没什么了？
Are you kidding? Me?
开玩笑吧？我？
- Yeah. - No.
- 是啊 - 怎么会
Anton is like totally gay.
人家是玩断背的
Harold, what are you doing here?
哈罗德，你怎么来这儿了？
I didn't want to wait ten days to see you...
我急着见你，等不到十天了
so I thought I would come and surprise you.
就想给你个惊喜
That is so sweet.
太感人了
OK. It's sweet.
是啊，太不易了
I've been thinking about you this whole time.
我一直都在想你呢
- You have? - I have.
- 真的？ - 真的
- I missed you so much. - I missed you.
- 想死你了 - 我也是
Fuck yeah, dude.
好耶，哥们
Bang bang, Roldy.
够水准，罗迪
Hello, Maria. My name is Kumar.
嗨，玛丽亚，我叫库马
- I've heard so much about you. - Hi.
- 久仰大名 - 嗨
This is Vanessa. Vanessa, Maria.
这是瓦内萨，瓦内萨，玛丽亚
- Hey. - Hey. How you doing?
- 嗨，你好
Ladies and Roldy, how would you like to get really fucking high...
女士们，罗迪，现在想想咱们去哪儿开心开心吧
since we're in Amsterdam?
既然来了阿姆斯特丹
- Yeah. - Shall we?
- 好啊 - 走吧？
- Sounds like a plan. - Let's do it.
- 有点意思 - 那就行动吧
Motherfucker!
干他娘的！